There we go. There we go. Can we please
give them a round of applause till we
get our own
like I said cuz we have put on the table
all that we need. All that we need. All
right. Happy Sabbath everybody.
>> Happy Sabbath.
>> All right. It's good to stand before you
on the Lord's Sabbath day. And what
we're going to do is uh like I said,
we're going to get into a topic that
hopefully should be very edifying. uh
because tomorrow is the feast of
Pentecost, right? And Pentecost is a
very intricate lesson. But if you don't
understand something as simple as what
we're going to deal with today, it'll
make it a little bit harder to
understand Pentecost tomorrow. So, cuz
tomorrow is a high Sabbath day because
there's weekly Sabbaths, that's what
this is. Tomorrow is what's called a
high Sabbath or a annual Sabbath day.
And they still kept them after Jesus
resurrected, right? That's why Acts
chapter 2 had all the disciples in one
place on one accord because they were
still keeping the high annual Sabbath
days. All right. So, what we're going to
do is we're going to deal with today's
topic which is the soul is the body, not
inside the body. The soul is the body,
not inside the body. So, what we're
going to do, we're going to have the
opening scriptures of the reading of the
law and we're going to get into today's
topic. So, and read for me today is my
esteem reading colleague, brother
Courtland. How you doing? How you doing?
>> Excellent. Excellent.
>> All right. Exodus 20 and verse one. And
we are going to do something that the
world considers very strange. We're
going to read the Bible.
>> I'm not just going to talk with in my
hands because if I did this and I just
ran my mouth, y'all be like, "Okay,
yeah, but how do I know what God says?"
No, we're going to read the Bible.
Exodus 20 verse1. When you get there, go
ahead and read.
>> And God spake all these words, saying,
>> "That's right.
>> I am the Lord thy God, which have
brought thee out of the land of Egypt,
>> right?
>> Out of the house of bondage.
>> Thou shalt have no other gods before me.
>> Thou shall have no other gods before
me." And we know that who this is
talking is Jesus Christ. Thou shalt have
no other gods before me. Go ahead. Thou
shall not make unto thee any graven
image, or any likeness of anything that
is in the heaven above, or that is in
the earth beneath, or that is in the
water under the earth.
>> Don't make some statues or images and
say that it's God. Go ahead.
>> Thou shall not bow thyself to them,
right? Nor serve them. For I, the Lord
thy God, am a jealous God.
>> That's right.
>> Visiting the iniquity of the fathers
upon the children unto the third and
fourth generation of them that hate me.
>> That's right. Go ahead. and showing
mercy unto thousands of them that love
me and keep my commandments.
>> How do you show you love them? By
keeping the commandments. Go ahead.
>> Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain.
>> Right.
>> For the Lord will not hold him guiltless
that taketh his name in vain.
>> That's right. Go ahead.
>> Remember the Sabbath day to keep it
holy.
>> That's what we're doing. Go ahead.
>> Six days shalt thy labor and do all thy
work. But the seventh day is the Sabbath
of the Lord thy God.
>> It didn't say the Sabbath of the Jews.
>> No. the Sabbath of the Lord thy God.
This is his day. Go ahead.
>> In it, thou shalt not do any work,
>> right?
>> Thou, nor thy son, nor thy daughter, thy
man's servant, nor thy maid servant, nor
thy cattle, nor thy stranger that is
within thy gates,
>> nor the strangers. Go ahead.
>> For in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that in them is,
and rested the seventh day.
>> That's right.
>> Wherefore the Lord blessed the Sabbath
day, and hallowed it.
>> And he never stopped blessing this day.
And he hasn't stopped making this day
holy. Go ahead.
>> Honor thy father and thy mother, that
thy days may be long upon the land which
the Lord thy God giveth thee.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Thou shall not kill.
>> Thou shall not commit adultery.
>> That's right.
>> Thou shall not steal. Right.
>> Thou shall not bear false witness
against thy neighbor. That's right. Thou
shall not coveret thy neighbor's house.
Thou shall not coveret thy neighbor's
wife, nor his man's servant, nor his
maid servant, nor his ox, nor his ass,
nor anything that is thy neighbors.
>> Right? That would set a utopia if you
kept those commandments. Let's go now to
Ecclesiastes chapter 12, and see if it
changed. Ecclesiastes, this is written
by King Solomon, the wisest man that
lived other than Christ.
Ecclesiastes 12, we'll read two verses,
verses 13 and 14. Let's see if it
changed. When you get there, go ahead
and read.
>> Let us hear the conclusion of the whole
matter.
matter. Go ahead.
>> Fear God and keep his commandments.
>> Fear God and keep his what?
>> Commandments.
>> Go ahead.
>> For this is the whole duty of man.
>> That is the whole meaning of life. Go
ahead.
>> For God shall bring every work into
judgment.
>> Into judgment. Go ahead.
>> With every secret thing,
>> right?
>> Whether it be good or whether it be
evil. It's been some evil that's been
done secretly that they not getting
away. They just getting by. Let's go now
to Revelation chapter 22. Let's go to
the last spot, which is the end of the
book, the last chapter of the last book,
and let's see if God has changed the
requirements to get salvation.
Revelation 22, and we're going to hit
two verses, verses 14 and 15. When you
get there, go ahead and read.
>> Blessed are they that do his
commandments.
commandments. Go ahead.
>> That they may have right to the tree of
life.
life. Go ahead.
>> And may enter in through the gates into
the city.
>> They are allowed entry. Go ahead.
>> For without are dogs,
>> Uhhuh.
>> and sorcerers, right,
>> and hormongers, and murderers,
>> and idoltors,
>> Uhhuh.
>> And whosoever loveth and maketh a lie.
>> And whosoever makes a lie. And whosoever
loves a lie that they made. I always
like giving that clarification.
>> Yes, sir.
>> But all these that we saw in verse 15
are people that broke the commandments
that's in the Old Testament.
>> Idolatry, sorcery,
mongering, murder, all this stuff.
Dogs. That's referring to homosexual
lifestyles. That's what's written in the
Old Testament. He said, "These are all
not getting in the kingdom."
>> So all So I'd rather give the truth than
give a comforting lie. So, with that
being said, uh like I said, uh we always
have those opening scriptures set the
foundation and we're going to deal now
with the soul is the body, not inside of
the body. This is one of those topics
that for those that have been around,
this is a very easy topic, but this one
topic stirs up so much confusion in all
these other churches because they don't
understand this one thing. And we're
going to show how it's misunderstood or
how it was done in error. But we're
going to show also how to correct that
error through the scriptures because the
Bible is what gives understanding. All I
have is an opinion. My opinion means
nothing. The Bible is the understanding
because of it says the scriptures is of
no private interpretation. So if we get
this foundation set, what it does is it
unlocks other understanding of different
prophecies all through the Bible. Old
testament it breaks down some
understanding that's written in the
gospels. you'll understand some things
that Paul's writing in his letters and
especially in Revelations. It's like,
okay, now that makes sense because if
you misunderstand this, you say, "Well,
then someone dies." They do what? They
go to heaven.
>> They say, "Well, that's the that that's
Sister Suz's shell. That's her body, but
her soul went somewhere else." That's
what they say.
>> But what we going to do, like I said,
we're going to do something very weird.
We're going to read. Let's go to Matthew
chap 10. Let's start in Matthew chapter
10 cuz we have to understand where the
confusion comes into place.
Matthew chapter 10. Like I said, I have
a few visuals as always and we'll just
try to help simplify some of these
points because it's not complex. This
this really is not a very complex
lesson. This is a corrective lesson. So,
if you get this corrected, just like if
you have an issue in your car, your
alternator's off or or go or or your
engine's overheating or whatever it is,
when you get that one issue fixed,
doesn't your car run better?
>> Yes.
>> That's what this is. This is a
corrective lesson because a lot of
people have check engine lights uh
spiritually from this one
misunderstanding. In fact, I spent a few
couple days going back and forth with an
individual who didn't have it under
didn't have it. I was trying to hold his
hand to show him the scriptures, but his
pride was so tough on him that he
couldn't learn nothing.
>> But the one thing that I find is that
when you have humility, then the Lord
can allow you to see something, but if
you're filled with pride, he won't let
you see nothing.
>> Did Nicodemus go up to the Lord and ask
him questions privately? And he
expounded some word of God to him. You
had Apollos, it said he was mighty in
the scriptures and and but what happened
is Priscilla and Aquilla pulled him
aside. It says, "And expound the word of
God unto him more perfectly." But what
if he was prideful? Then he ain't going
to receive nothing. Same thing. Same
thing. Matthew chapter 10. And I want
one verse. Verse 28. 10 and 28. When you
get there, go ahead and read.
>> And fear not them which kill the body.
>> Jesus is saying, "Don't fear them that
can kill the body." Go ahead.
>> But are not able to kill the soul.
>> But are not able to kill the soul. Go
ahead. but rather fear him which is able
to destroy both soul and body in hell.
>> See, brother Jared, Jesus said,
"Don't fear them that could kill the
body but can't kill the soul." But see,
they keep forgetting that Matthew is not
the only one that heard this
conversation. Sometimes you have someone
that can hear this side and someone else
to hear the same conversation and hear
that other side. So, what we're going to
do is we're going to take a look at this
because what I'm what I'm going to do is
I'm just going to make it plain with see
they'll say CJ the body can die but the
soul can't die.
I always wonder okay well what you going
No, I don't want to get too far ahead of
myself. All I'mma say is we're going to
put this to the test. Is that fair?
>> Yes, sir. Let's get let's hear what Luke
said because Luke heard the same
conversation. Let's go now to Luke
chapter 12. Luke chapter 12.
But all we're all we're showing is that
this here and and you know who really uh
solidifies this misunderstanding?
Hollywood.
All them movies, all those cartoons.
I'll talk about that one movie that had
Patrick Sees, Deme Moore, and Whoopy
Goldberg. What was the name of that
movie?
>> Ghost.
>> Ghost. They solidified that.
I I could go on and on and on because
what what this is this actually, believe
it or not, this comes from Hinduism.
What do you mean, brother Jared? Comes
from Hinduism. This is called
transmigration.
Hinduist and Buddhists believe in
transmigration,
but that's what this is. Another time
they'll call it something called OBBE,
outer body uh uh uh uh uh experience or
sometimes they'll call it astral
projection. Uh what's the other uh
Marvel movie? Doctor Strange. They did a
whole lot of that, but it's Hollywood,
not Bible. So when you take a Hollywood
mindset and try to read into the Bible,
you decimate and make a mess of
prophecy. But we going to let the Bible
put it all in the correct order. Luke
12, I said, right? Luke 12 and verse 4.
12 and verse4 because God is the best
teacher. And we going to see that over
and over. When you get there, go ahead
and read.
>> And I say unto you, my friend,
>> Uhhuh. be not afraid of them that kill
the body,
>> right?
>> And after that have no more that they
can do.
>> Okay. He's Now, he didn't make a
differentiation between body and soul,
did he? Did did Luke?
>> No.
>> No. Because cuz what I'm showing is
they say that, okay, this could be
killed, but the soul can live on. Cuz
they'll say, well, number one, they'll
say the soul's inside of you,
>> right?
>> But then they'll then when you ask them
where, they can never give it a specific
answer. Someone will try to get smart
and try to say, "Well, it's the pineal
gland behind your cerebral cortex." No,
no, it's not. I'll just tell you what
they do. Like I said, but they'll say he
he didn't make a differentiation. Luke
didn't make a differentiation. Matthew
did. So, we're going to when you have
two different accounts, that means you
have to really search it out. Go ahead
and give me verse four from the top one
more time.
>> And I say unto you, my friends, be not
afraid of them that kill the body.
>> Right?
>> And after that, have no more that they
can do.
>> Okay. Go ahead.
>> But I will forewarn you whom ye shall
fear.
>> He said, "And now I'mma tell you who you
should fear." Go ahead.
>> Fear him which after he have killed
killed killed have power to cast into
hell. Yay, I say unto you,
>> fear the one that after someone has been
killed, he has power to cast you even to
hell. Mean in other words, even into the
lake of fire. He said that's the one who
you should fear. So now we see this, but
we're going to we're going to put this
to the test. So we we heard Matthew's
account. We heard Luke's account. Let's
read some more Bible to see which one
heard it better. Let's go to Revelation
19. Revelation chapter 19. Because it
said about watch out for the one that
can throw you in that fire. Let's see
when the fire is available for someone
to be thrown into, what is thrown in the
fire. Just the same way if I'm cooking a
recipe, right? Uh, do I throw this in
the pot or do I put that in the pot? Do
I use this in the gumbo recipe or do I
use that? Let's see what he threw in the
pot. Revelation chapter 19. Revelation
19. Like I said,
many years ago when this was fixed in my
understanding, it's like all of a sudden
all these doors and other scriptures
started opening up and I said, "Now I
get this. Now I get that. Now I
understand how King Saul was deceived by
speaking to the woman with a familiar
spirit at Endor. Because Saul thought he
was talking to Samuel, but that was not
Samuel he was talking to. He was talking
to a fallen angel and God killed him for
it. But the fallen angel looked like it
was Samuel. So fallen angels are trick.
They they do trickery. They do all types
of things to deceive men.
>> Right?
>> People forgot about that. that there's
one-third of angels here on earth
deceiving humans
or attempting to Revelation 19 and verse
11. When you get there, go ahead and
read.
>> And I saw heaven open, right?
>> And behold, a white horse, and he that
and he that sat upon him was called
faithful and true.
>> Faithful and true. It's Jesus. Go ahead.
>> And in his righteousness, he doeth judge
and make war.
>> Hold on. Hold on. I thought he was
coming back giving hugs and care bears
>> and high fives.
>> Make war. He said he's coming back to
judge and make war. Interesting. Go
ahead.
>> His eyes were as a flame of fire and on
his head were many crowns.
>> And on his head was many crowns. Go
ahead.
>> And he had a name written that no man
knew but he himself.
>> That's right.
>> And he was clothed with a vesture dipped
in blood.
>> Dipped in blood. Uh-huh.
>> And his name is called the word of God.
>> That dipped in blood is letting you know
he's going to slay a lot of people at
his return for mishandling his word. Go
ahead. And the armies which were in
heaven followed him upon white horses
clothed in fine linen, white and clean.
>> Uhhuh. So they going these are armies
coming from uh the second heaven. But
let's go now to verse 19. I want to get
right to what's going to happen because
this mankind is not they it's like they
cannot conceive that you know we're at
the last days and we're about to try to
fight Christ. That is exactly what
mankind is about to do. They don't know
that because they think the person over
in Rome is a holy person and he is one
of the first people going to Lake of
Fire. But we can't tell them nothing.
Why? Because we go to church on
Saturday.
[laughter]
Go ahead.
>> And I saw the beast and the kings of the
earth and their armies gathered together
to make war against him that
>> you will make war against Christ is
coming on a white horse and all these
armies. That's how far their
understanding has gone. It's out. Go
ahead. make war against him that's set
on the horse and against his army.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And the beast was taken and with him the
false prophet.
>> The beast is the secular or military
leader. And then you have the false
prophet. That's the religious guy that
always wears all white wherever he goes.
The false prophet the B Bible calls him.
Go ahead.
>> That rough miracles before him.
>> But brother Jay, he's doing miracles.
The Bible called it false miracles.
Don't you know that that fallen angels
can do that still?
>> Yep. When Pharaoh had his magicians,
then they do some miracles. Yep.
>> And signs. But people think because it's
a miracle that it came from God. And
they don't understand that Satan got a
team, too.
>> That's all we showing. Go ahead. With
which he deceived them that had received
the mark of the beast.
>> He deceived them with the miracles. He
didn't deceive them with the word of God
BECAUSE THEY DON'T HAVE THE word of God.
That's why they had to use the miracles,
the theatrics, pyrochnics.
Go ahead.
>> And them that worshiped his image.
>> Uh-huh.
>> These both were cast alive into a lake
of fire, burning with brimstone.
>> They were cast alive into the what?
>> Lake of fire.
>> There. So, excuse my little images, but
here we have two individuals that was
thrown into the LAKE OF FIRE BY Jesus
Christ directly. That means he's like,
I'm not waiting for judgment day. I'm
putting them in the fire now at his
return. So, now that we see this happen,
I want to see, well, what was thrown in
the fire? Let's go now to Isaiah 66.
Okay. Did Did he Did he take the body
and throw it in the fire or did he take
the soul OUT OF HIS MOUTH AND THROW IT
IN THE FIRE? What was thrown in the
fire? I mean, surely God would knowing
that God created us. He knows what we
are comprised of, right?
He How do I know that so? Well, because
he's the first surgeon. Who where did we
get Eve from? God put Adam to sleep and
took out a rib and made he a woman. Did
it say that he took a rib out and he
took some pieces of his soul so she
would have a soul in her? It just said
he took a rib, didn't he? This is This
is very simple, but it's complex if you
never heard it.
Isaiah 66. Isaiah 66.
Because we deal from Genesis to
Revelations.
Isaiah 66 and verse1 15. Well, brother
Jared, why do I go? Why you read that
Old Testament to me? Didn't he fulfill
it all? He fulfilled a portion pertain
to his sacrifice. He has not fulfilled
the scriptures about his return yet.
That's like someone saying, "Oh, don't
worry about you don't do that homework
assignment. you ain't going to be graded
on it. The teacher like, "Yes, you are."
I don't know who told you that.
>> Isaiah 66 and verse 15. When you get
there, go ahead and read.
>> For behold, the Lord will come with
fire, with his chariots like a whirlwind
to render his anger with fury, and his
rebuke with flames of fire.
>> You saw where it said chariots, didn't
we just read in Revelation 19, he going
to come back with his armies? That's
them right there. Go ahead.
For by fire and by his sword will the
Lord plead with all flesh.
>> Right. Go ahead.
>> And the slain of the Lord shall be many.
>> The slain of the Lord. That's why it
said he had a vesture dipped in blood
cuz he going to have a lot of blood on
his raignment when he gets done killing
so many people. But they don't know
about this Jesus. Go ahead.
>> They they sanctify themselves and purify
themselves in the garden behind one tree
in the midst.
>> In other words, they listen to that one
tree in the midst. What one tree? the
tree in the midst of the Garden of Eden,
which was the tree of knowledge of good
and evil. Don't eat from that tree. In
other words, don't listen to Satan. Cuz
what fruit are we told not to eat from?
Hosea 10 says it's the fruit of lies.
But people are still eating from that
tree and they aren't holding a
pomegranate or an apple. In other words,
they're still consuming lies which he
said don't listen to him. He's a liar
and the father of it,
>> right?
>> He abode not in the truth. Go ahead.
>> Eating swine's flesh.
>> Eating what?
>> Swine's flesh.
>> Well, God told us not to do that. Who's
[snorts] walking the earth telling you
to do that? He said, "Watch out. Go
ahead."
>> And the abomination
>> and the abomination. Go ahead.
>> And the mouse.
>> And the mouse. Go ahead.
>> Be consumed together.
>> Right. So if someone say, "Well, see,
uh, I don't eat mice, but I sure do love
some shrimp." That's abomination.
>> So you can't make that distinction
between which is which. He already told
you what is already considered food and
what's not. Go ahead.
>> Sayaith the Lord.
>> Sayeth the Lord. End of 17.
>> That's the end of 17.
>> Keep going.
>> For I know their works and their
thoughts. It shall come that I would
gather all nations and tongues, and they
shall come and see my glory.
>> Yep. Everybody going to have to come see
his glory. Right. But jump down to verse
22 for the sake of time. 22. Go ahead.
>> For as the new heavens and the new earth
which I will make,
>> which we don't have yet. This is not the
new heaven and the new earth yet. If
that's the case, I shouldn't be able to
go to see the inner harbor and it look
black like sludge. This can't be new
heaven and new earth yet.
>> Go ahead.
>> Shall remain before me.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Sayth the Lord. So shall your seed and
your name remain.
>> So shall your seed and your name remain.
23.
>> And it shall come to pass that from one
new moon to another, and from one
Sabbath to another shall all flesh come
to worship before me. Shall just the
Jews come before me? Did it say that?
>> No.
>> What did it say?
>> Shall all flesh?
>> All flesh. So it doesn't matter what
your nationality is. You have to go
report and see Jesus or have a
representative go and report to see
Jesus when he's back in Jerusalem. Go
ahead.
>> Before me, sayith the Lord.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And they shall go forth and look upon
the carcasses of the men that have
transgressed against him.
>> Hold on. And when you go there, you'll
be able to go look and see the
carcasses. What is a carcass? a body.
You will be able to see the carcasses of
the men that transgressed against me.
Who are these men? The beast and the
false prophet. We can show you that from
the temple mount, you can see where the
lake of fire will be. It's called in the
valley of Henam. And you'll be able to
see those two men still burning year
after year after year after year. Every
time you come to keep a feast day back
in Jerusalem, now you keep seeing those
same men burning as an example. The
carcass though, but it said we saw
earlier he said they were cast alive.
Right.
>> Correct.
>> But that's how we know that it was the
body that was thrown in the fire. That's
why it said there shall be weeping and
nashing of teeth. Those are body
elements, not a puff of smoke that
floats out of you. I don't know where
that comes from, but less uh that's uh
finish out verse 24.
>> For their worms shall not die. Now the
worms that eating on them don't die
either. Go ahead.
>> Neither shall their fire be quenched.
>> And the fire doesn't go out once Jesus
lights the fuse. That's another lesson
though. Go ahead.
>> And they shall be in abhoring unto all
flesh.
>> Everybody's going to be like, "Oh my
goodness, I do not want what do I need
to do God?" That see that's when they
want to listen. They don't want to
listen today because they don't see this
fire yet. Because you don't see the fire
until he brings it forth in Jerusalem
and puts the pope and the European
leader European Union leader in the
fire.
Two Gentiles are going to beat everybody
to the fire. Even beat Satan to the fire
because Satan doesn't go until after the
10,00 years. A thousand years in the
fire before Satan. But let's go now to
Leviticus 5. Leviticus 5.
Cuz now I just saw
no distinction between soul and body. I
see a carcass. In other words, the whole
thing thrown in the fire.
So if they're in the fire, well that
carcass is just a shell, Jar. Well, then
where does the soul go if that's the
case? If they're already in the fire, is
there a second lake of fire that they go
to? No. That's your that's the last
stop. Once you hit that lake of fire,
you cannot get out of it. I don't care
what the Catholics has told you about
purgatory. You are stuck.
>> That's why uh uh Luke 16 through the
parable with Abraham, he said, "There's
a great golf fix that you can't pass
over here and we can't pass to you. So I
can't sin Lo give you a drop of water on
your tongue. It's all right. Can't help
it. Cannot help. Leviticus 5. Leviticus
5. And what we're going to do now is
we're going to let the Bible continually
do the teaching of what is what. How am
I going to tell?
Let's say I got a Chevy truck and it's
acting up, right? I'm going to tell
Chevy, "Nah, you should have did this.
You should have did that." They're the
one that built the vehicle,
>> right?
>> Why don't you let them tell you what's
going on with your vehicle? No, we think
we're the creator. No, we're not.
>> Leviticus 5. That's why that I have a
hard time with hearing that evolution
talk because they're telling God that
you don't know what you've made. I've
evolved from monkeys. Then if that's the
case, why do we still have monkeys and
baboons still?
Why didn't they finish evolving
crickets?
>> Because they don't know that they that
evolution is a theory. And there's six
different kinds that they refer to, but
macroeolution
is not proven. Microeolution is saying
that well there's a poodle and then
there's a a Rottweiler and they have
different variations within the same
family. But I can't say that the German
Shepherd came from a dinosaur. That's
macro evolution. They can't prove that.
That's why I said we have no problem
going there with this uh conversation
because the Bible is the main teacher.
Leviticus 5 and verse one. When you get
there, go ahead and read.
>> And if a soul sin,
>> if a soul sin, go ahead.
>> And hear the voice of swearing.
>> Hold on. Hold up. That means a soul must
have ears,
>> right?
>> How can a soul hear? That's supposed to
be inside you.
>> Your body has ears though,
>> right?
>> So if a soul hears, go ahead and is a
witness whether he have seen or known of
it.
>> If he do not utter it, then he shall
bear his iniquity. iniquity, right? Give
me verse two as well.
>> Or if a soul touch any unclean thing.
>> Hold up, hold up, hold up. Now, I have a
hand, but how can my soul come forth and
touch something unless the body is the
soul?
>> Like I said in the movie Ghost, every
time he tried to grab the water, his
hand would go through it. He can't touch
nothing. But apparently the body, which
is a soul, can
>> right
>> go ahead. Whether it be a carcass of a
unclean beast, right?
>> Or a carcass of a unclean cattle or the
carcass of unclean creeping things,
right? And if it be hidden from him, he
also shall be unclean and guilty.
>> Uh-huh. Jump down to verse four. Go
ahead.
>> Or if a soul swear pronouncing with his
lips to
>> pronounce it with his what?
>> Lips.
>> Hold up. Souls have lips. Now I need to
find out what in the world is this soul
that can hear, touch, and speak or swear
with his lips. If that hold on, if you
can swear, that means you have a tongue.
>> Correct.
>> Cuz you can't talk without a tongue.
>> So apparently there's a lot of other
body parts that come with the soul. Go
ahead.
>> To do evil or to do good,
>> right?
>> Whatsoever it be that a man shall
pronounce with an oath or it be hid from
him.
>> Hold up. What? whatsoever it be that a
man, this talking about human, in other
words, man or woman,
a man shall pronounce with the oath. Go
ahead.
>> And it be hid from him when he knoweth
of it, then he shall be guilty.
>> And give me verse five. Go ahead.
>> He shall be guilty in all in one of
these.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And it shall be when he shall be guilty
in one of these things that he shall
confess that he have sinned in that
thing. In other words, there's some
things that you do in ignorance and you
have no knowledge of. Well, you are not
held guilty according to that. But when
God has told you something and you went
against it anyways, he said that's when
it's become sin. That's when you can
become guilty of something. That's why
the Bible speaks about the blood
covering those that have sinned in
ignorance. So, that's what we're seeing
here. But, uh, so now we realize that a
soul can sin and get you in trouble. So,
I need to know what this thing is that
can sin. Let's go to Isaiah 51. Isaiah
51. Like I said, we
I'm trying not to overkill, but this is
one of those things that if you get this
not untied in your understanding, it
really opens up so many different areas
of the Bible and it puts everything in
its proper order. Then you'll know what
to do when you go into Revelation and it
talks about every living soul died in
the sea. And you'll know what it's been
talking about,
>> right? Because those fish and animals
and whales and everything in the sea,
right? They have souls or they have
bodies.
>> Right
>> now, I can put everything in its proper
place. But if you got that false
doctrine, then that's going to be that
door going to be shut to you. You don't
know what to do with that verse. So, you
just say, "Let's not turn to the book of
Revelations no more."
[laughter]
Isaiah 51 and verse 21. And I came from
one of those churches. I came from Mount
Olive Missionary Baptist Church
and where Pastor Ben McClinton never
touched Revelations,
>> but he was there while my mother was
there, while my grandparents was there.
And so you you know they there for a
long time and won't touch that book
until the Lord knocked on my door and
said, "Come follow me. Here I am."
Isaiah 51 and 21. When you get there, go
ahead and read.
>> Therefore, hear now this.
>> Hear now this. Go ahead.
>> Thou afflicted and drunken, but not with
wine.
>> In other words, because that's what
happened to the children of Israel. They
went through affliction, and they've
been drunken with false doctrine. Go
ahead.
>> Thus sayith the Lord, the Lord and thy
thy God that plead that causes of his
people.
>> In other words, the one that's pleased
your case or your representation. Go
ahead.
>> Behold, I have taken out of thy hand the
cup of trembling. Now, this cup of
trembling, this hasn't happened yet.
This is the future. The cup of trembling
is all the affliction that the children
of Israel went through. It's like you
you just drank some elixir, but it says
when you drink it, all of a sudden you
tremble, but it's not a physical thing.
That's all why they're drunk. It was not
a physical wine. In other words, it's
showing that you are drinking the cup of
his wrath now. But he's going to have
you stop drinking from that cup and he's
going to give it to the people that's
afflicting the children of Israel and
say, "It's your turn to drink from this
cup. This happens in the future,
specifically after the sixth seal. Go
ahead.
>> Even the dregs of the cup of my fury.
>> The dregs of my fury. Go ahead.
>> Thou shalt no more drink it again.
>> Right. Cuz at the end of the great
tribulation, he says, "Your uh it's
enough. You've drank enough from that
cup. It's their turn now." Go ahead.
>> But I will put it into the hand of them
that afflicted thee,
>> right?
>> Which have said to thy soul.
>> And now these people that afflict you,
what did they say to your soul? Go
ahead.
>> Bow down.
>> Bow down. Go ahead.
>> That we may go over.
>> Bow down so I can get across this
puddle. Go ahead.
>> And thou hast laid the body as the
ground.
>> Hold up. If they said to the soul, bow
down. Then why are they laying the body
on the ground that they could step over
it? Because the soul is the body. Go
ahead. And that's the street to them
that went over.
>> Right. To them that went over. We I'm
seeing a whole lot of correlation
between this body and the soul. Let's go
backwards to Genesis chapter 2.
So they said, "I want to go across this
street, this puddle, this walkway. Lay
down so I don't mess up my shoes."
But what I saw lay down was the body.
Even though they said lay your soul
down. Can you take your soul out and
say, "Okay, there I just laid the soul
down, but I'm standing up." No, because
it's one and the same. This is what the
Bible screams all I mean literally all
over the Bible. We have so many lessons
where it's screaming information across
the Bible. But that's why he said he
blessed and sanctified the Sabbath day.
You learn more on this day than any
other day of the week. I guarantee it. I
guarantee it.
Genesis chapter 2.
Genesis chapter 2. See, the Lord said he
gonna give that repayment. That's why
when I saw I think it was this past
week, Pope says, "Well, we for we ask
for an apology or we apologize rather
and ask for forgiveness for the Catholic
Church's role in the slave trade."
Didn't they say that this week? Right.
>> That is accurate.
>> And when they did that, that's not up to
me. That's the Lord got to handle that.
He said he's going to do what we just
read in Isaiah 51. They have to drink
from that cup because we had to drink
from that cup.
>> Correct.
>> I don't blame them because we disobeyed
God. That's why God brought the
affliction as he as he for told us. But
we see that now they starting to at
least acknowledge. Yeah. Maybe we had a
part to play. Of course you did. You
gave the papal bull called doomed divers
that allowed them to go and get them
from Africa and bring them over to
America. We know the history cuz we read
here
>> Genesis 2 and 7. 2 and 7. And when you
get there, go ahead and read.
>> And the Lord God formed man of the dust
of the ground.
>> The Lord God formed man from the what?
>> Dust of the ground.
>> Okay. Dust, dirt, same thing. And what
did he do from there? Go ahead.
>> And brea breathed into his nostrils the
breath of life.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And man became a living soul.
>> Hold on. And man became Or did it say
and he inserted into man a soul? Did it
say that?
>> I see it say it's became.
>> It said he became. Right. So that means
you have the breath of God, which is one
thing, and dirt. That is the sum total
of who you are. That's it. I've never
seen someone say, "Well, we not to you
need to do this operation on the table
up. The soul's trying to leave. Catch
it. Put it back in.
Stitch it. Stitch it."
I've never seen that. Right. They every
time they Hey, we need to remove the
spleen. We need to do this. We need to
Whatever they're doing, they do that
surgery, right? But they never catch
anything jumping out because that we
just read Genesis of what? We were made
of dirt and the breath of God. That's
it. And it said man became a what soul?
>> Living soul.
>> Living soul. Because there's something
called a dead soul. Cuz I was told well
brother J see the soul don't die. You
haven't read no Bible.
Man became a living soul when he
received the breath of God. So let's go
take a look at this breath concerning
the soul. Let's go to Psalms 104 and
verse 23. Psalm 104 and 23.
Psalm 104 and 23. And before we get out
of here, we are going to take a very
good look at Jesus soul.
We are going to take a very good look at
Jesus soul before we get out of here.
Psalm 104
and 23. My apologies. I had a visual to
show.
You were comprised. You were first
formed
and then the breath went into his
nostrils.
Don't want to skip that.
So Psalm 104 and 23. When you get there,
go ahead and read.
>> Man going forth unto his work and into
his labor until the evening.
>> Uh-huh. We go to work. Go ahead.
>> Skip.
>> Oh, yeah. Uh, yeah. Go ahead. Skip to
28. Yeah. 28. Thank you.
>> That thou givest them, they gather.
>> When God gives us something, we gather.
Go ahead.
>> Thou openest thy hand, they are filled
with good.
>> When he opens his hand, it's like, yo,
bank account just got blessed or
something else came came your way. That
mean he opened his hand unto you. Go
ahead. We, in other words, we receive
everything that we have. Go ahead. Thou
hideest thy face, they are troubled.
>> But when he hides his face from us, in
other words, like turning his back, we
in trouble. Go ahead.
>> Thou take us away their breath, they die
and return to their dust.
>> Hold up. When you take away your their
what?
>> Breath.
>> And what happens after that?
>> They die and return to their dust.
>> So in order for to their uh be a dead
soul, you have to take away the breath.
And then they start returning to the
dust. But you notice that it didn't say
that you they take you take away their
soul. Did it say that? It just said
their breath because we need to know
what that breath is. I'm just like I
said, I'm trying to make it so simple.
That was the end of 29.
>> That was the end of 29.
>> Perfect. Let's go to uh Luke 23 now.
Luke 23.
this all over the Bible.
Luke 23
and we're going to pick it up at verse
44.
That's why we I think we have I I
probably seen close to 15 plus different
variations of understanding death and
life and resurrection that we have at
the Israel of God because we could hit
this in so many different variations and
angles. Um, sometimes we we you could
show it from just a Jesus angle. You can
show it from all through the Old
Testament. You can show it through
prophecy. You can show it through
previous people. You can use examples
and and ask the question about Lot.
Well, what his wife was turn into salt,
right? Where did her soul go?
Her soul became salt cuz she is the
soul. You can, like I say, it's all over
the Bible.
They take away that breath. They
returned to the dust. Luke 23 and 44. 23
and 44. When you get there, go ahead and
read.
>> And it was about the sixth hour. And
there was darkness over all the earth
until the 9inth hour.
>> Uh-huh. This is the time when Jesus on
the cross. Go ahead.
>> And the sun was darkened, and the veil
of the temple was rent in the midst. And
when Jesus had cried with a loud voice,
he said, "Father, into thy hands I
command
comm commen my spirit." He said,
"Father, into thy hands I commend my
what?"
>> Spirit.
>> Now, hold on. It seems like we throwing
in another equation here. First, it was
body or soul. But then it's like, well,
hold on. Where the spirit come from now,
right?
>> Right.
>> So, now we see body because some people
will use that and say, see, man is in
three parts. Body, soul, and spirit
because they don't always understand
what this is referring to. But we will.
What verse we at?
>> We're in the middle of 46.
>> Go ahead.
>> And having said thus, he gave up the
ghost.
>> Right. And after having said that, he
gave up the what?
>> Ghost.
>> Now, see, THEY DON'T KNOW WHAT THAT IS.
They say, "See, Brother J, what about
this ghost here?" Ghost is slang for
spirit. Same thing. That's why he said,
"I commend my spirit." But then what did
he give up? He gave up the ghost. So if
I said, um, "Brother Courtland, you can
borrow my DVD on this subject." You
know, I'm old school. I still got DVDs,
right?
>> But then I give him a separate DVD on
something else. No, it's the same thing.
It just has another different word for
it, spirit and or ghost. But we're going
to see what this is. Let's go now to
Ecclesiastes 12.
Ecclesiastes 12
because now it's like well after I have
demystified soul and just made it what
it is this is what I call moving the
goalpost they move to well the spirit is
what's mystical now right
you got to do spirit fingers spirit
[laughter]
Ecclesiastes 12 Ecclesiastes 12
and we're going to pick it up at verse
one. 12 and 1. When you get there, go
ahead and read.
>> Remember now thy creator in the days of
thy youth.
>> Right? In other words, remember Lord
while you young. Go ahead.
>> While the evil days come nigh,
>> right?
>> Nor the years draw nigh when thy shall
say, I have no pleasure ending. In other
words, before you have to walk with a
cane and it take you a little bit of
time to move around, he said, "Remember
why you young?" I remember uh I was
playing uh basketball. One of my
basketball assistant coaches would tell
me, he said, "Jerry, why are you doing
all this religious stuff? You 16. Why
don't you go out and live a little and
then come back when you can't?" I was
16. I said, "How do I know how much time
that I have?" As if he could guarantee
it to me,
>> right? So I did what I could with what I
knew and I still believe that we say
keep that same energy. Right? So do this
while you know while you have some youth
to do all types of things for the Lord.
Jump down to verse five. Go ahead.
>> Also when they shall be afraid of that
which is high and fear shall be in the
way and the almond tree shall flourish.
>> In other words you when you're older a
lot of things are become challenges. So
now you get fearful of how you have to
move around based on these obstacles
because you don't have that youth. Go
ahead.
>> And the grasshopper shall be a burden
and desire shall fail,
>> right?
>> Because man goeth to his long home.
>> Man goes to his long home which is the
graveyard. Go ahead.
>> And the mourers go about the streets.
>> And then the mourers go about the
streets after they commit the body to
the ground. But jump down to verse
seven. Go ahead.
>> Then shall the dust return to the earth
as it was. Uh, so there at that time,
the one that has passed away, the dust
returns unto the earth. Go ahead.
>> And the spirit shall return unto God who
gave it.
>> Now, it didn't say breath here, did it?
>> No.
>> It said the spirit shall return to God
who gave it. Right.
>> Yes.
>> But we read that when he takes away
their breath, they return to their dust.
Right.
>> Correct.
>> Maybe the breath and the spirit is the
same thing.
A lot of people don't know this. That's
why you don't see any dead people
breathing.
Simplicity. This is simple. Let's go now
to Luke chapter 8.
Luke chapter 8. So, we saw what happens
when we take away that spirit, right?
>> Yep.
>> Let's see if we add that spirit. Luke
chapter 8. Luke chapter 8.
And we're going to pick it up at verse
40. Luke 8 and verse 40.
When you get there, go ahead and read.
>> And it came to pass that when Jesus w
was returned, the people gladly received
him, right?
>> For they were all waiting for him.
>> Right?
>> And behold, there came a man named
Jarius, and he was a ruler of the
synagogue.
>> Right? So Gyrus is the ruler of the
synagogue, right? So remember, he he's
one of the people that didn't really
want was believe in Christ because a lot
of them were rejecting Christ until his
own family member is sick. Now he
kicking into motion, let me go holl at
Jesus cuz I heard he healing people. Go
ahead.
>> And he fell down at Jesus' feet, right?
>> And besought him that he would come into
his house,
>> right?
>> For he had one only daughter about 12
years of age, and she lay dying.
>> And she laid dying. Go ahead. But as he
went, as he went, the people thronged
him. A
>> as he went, the people throng. In other
words, he's trying to get to Jesus, but
it's a crowd. So, I'm fighting to trying
to get through this crowd, right? Jump
down to verse 49. 49. Go ahead.
>> While he yet spake, there cometh one
from the ruler of the synagogue's house,
saying to him, "Thy daughter is dead.
Trouble not the master."
>> So, he's like, "Your daughter has
already died. Give it up. Don't even
trouble him. Go ahead."
But when Jesus heard it, he answered
him, saying, "Fear not. Believe only,
and she shall be made whole."
>> That's all you got to do. Go ahead.
>> And when he came into the house, he
suffered no man to go in save Peter and
James and John and the father and the
mother of the maiden.
>> Uh-huh. Cuz sometimes when you doing
some of the serious work, you can't take
a whole crowd with you cuz not everyone
believes. So he go So he has a handful
of people. Go ahead. and all wealth and
bewailed her. But he said, "Weep not.
She is not dead but sleepeth."
>> Right? Everybody crying over her. She's
12 years old. A 12-y old girl has died.
And he's like, and everyone's crying,
but he said, "Don't weep. She is not
dead, but sleepeth. Go ahead."
>> And they laughed him to scorn knowing
that she was dead.
>> Now, that quick they went from mourning
and crying and wailing to laughing and
and pointing at Jesus. I'm showing what
the mindset is. Go ahead. And he put
them all out.
>> And that's what you have to do when you
have non-believers. When you get ready
to do the work of God, you got to get
them out because this is a whole
separate operation. YOU DON'T BELIEVE?
OKAY, COOL. GO. We'll do this without
you. Go ahead.
>> And took her by the hand and called
saying made arise.
>> Made arise. Go ahead.
>> And her spirit came again. And she
>> what came again?
>> Her spirit. So we just read that if you
take away their spirit they return to
the dust but she has died and then the
spirit came again and what happened and
she arose straightway.
>> And she arose straight way. Hold on.
Hold up.
He said made arise. And it says she
arose. Right. Arise means to come up cuz
she was like laying down. He's bringing
her up. Right.
>> Right.
>> Did he say made
come down hither from heaven? Did he say
that?
>> Because ain't nobody in heaven.
>> Correct. But the father, Jesus, and the
holy angels. He said, "Arise. Go ahead."
>> And he commanded to give her meat.
>> Now give her something to eat. Go ahead.
>> And her parents were astonished.
>> Right.
>> But he charged them that they should
tell no man what was done.
>> Now you know. [laughter]
You say, "Don't tell nobody." Now you
know. soon as he step out the room. Now
you on the two-way girl, you won't
believe. Woo! And let me tell you this,
right? So he know what he doing. And
then so the word went out, this man is
not just healing, he's raising the dead
as well. But if they had read Ezekiel
37, he said, it says, "You shall know
that I am God when I have opened your
graves and caused you to come OUT OF
YOUR GRAVES." THAT'S OLD TESTAMENT. But
everyone wasn't reading it that well.
Which means today we we really far away
from it. That's the end of verse 55.
That's the end.
>> Perfect. Let's go now to Job 27. So this
spirit is very interesting. If I take it
away, they die. If I add it to a dead
person, they come back to life. What is
this spirit?
Job 27.
That's why I love the fact that the
Sabbath day is all day because there's a
lot of information that you can sharpen
your word of God with or your sword
within the word of God. Cuz if it was
only just a couple hours and I go back
to watching the football game, then I'm
not really exercising myself in the
spirit and the deep things in this book
and or I'm not sharing it with y'all.
But because that it's a all day thing,
it's all about spiritual conversation.
Job 27 and verse one. 27 and 1. When you
get there, go ahead and read.
>> Moreover, Job continued his parable and
said,
>> Job continued his parable and said, what
did he say?
>> As God liveth,
>> right?
>> Who have taken away my judgment,
>> And the Almighty who have vexed my soul.
>> Hold up. Job's soul was vexed. I wonder
what soul had boils on it.
>> That was his body. Go ahead.
>> All the while my breath is in me.
>> All the while my breath is in me. Go
ahead.
>> And the spirit of God is in my nostrils.
But it said he breathed into man's
nostrils and he became a living soul. So
the breath and the spirit are synonymous
and one in the same WHICH ACTIVATES YOUR
BODY. This is this is simple, but we
just need to reread it. Read that verse
three again from the top.
>> Verse three. All the while, my breath is
in me.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And the spirit of God is in my nostrils.
>> Because God is one who holds your breath
and decides when to take it away. Go
ahead. Verse four.
>> My lips shall not speak wickedness.
>> While I'm living, I'm not going to speak
wickedness. Go ahead.
>> Nor my tongue utter deceit. And I'm not
going to be lying out here while the
Lord has given me breath to breathe.
That's what we seeing here. Let's go to
Isaiah chapter 2. Isaiah chapter 2. Cuz
that's how the Bible says to follow it
down to get this understanding of
doctrine. Read here a little, read there
a little, line upon line, precept upon
precept, and that's how you put this
thing together.
Especially the prophecies cuz there's
some parts of the Bible that you read
like history like going through what
happened with Joseph and his brothers,
right? You can read that right through,
right? But when you hit the prophets,
you got to know which one to hit
>> because it is not like a regular book.
The whole Bible is not like a regular
book. That's why when people try to use
it like that, they say, "Well,
Revelation is the end." But you know
what I call the book of Revelations? I
call the book of Revelations the
boomerang book. Because when you hear
certain things in the book of
Revelations, you got to go back to
Oadiah. You read this over here, you got
to go back to Job. Read this over there,
you got to go back to Genesis to go read
what they talking about. It's the
boomerang book. But if you say it's the
end, then you have no idea because the
book of Revelation doesn't even give
full understanding what's happening
during Jesus millennium reign and his
kingdom. That's why people think they go
straight to the father's kingdom because
you got to go back to the Old Testament
to see Jesus kingdom.
Isaiah 2 and verse 22. I want that one
verse 2 and 22. When you get that, when
you get there, go ahead and read.
>> C she for man.
>> Ce from man. Go ahead.
>> Whose breath is in his nostrils?
>> Whose is in his nostrils?
>> Breath.
>> That's why when someone is flatlining at
the hospital, they say clear. Boom.
[sighs]
That spirit be coming back. Then it
don't flatline no more. It's a beep
beep. This is I mean this is simp. And
I'm not even a a medical person, but I'm
like, THAT MAKES SO MUCH SENSE. SEE,
what we're doing is we're removing the
spookery out of the gospel. Now, it's
practical. The spookery is what makes
atheists say, "I can't believe that
because it doesn't make sense."
That's the end of that verse.
>> No, we're in the middle.
>> Finish it out.
>> For wherein is he to be accounted for?
>> For where shall he be accounted of?
Let's go see another example. Now, guess
what? This is in the future. This hasn't
even happened yet. Go to Revelation 11.
This is in the future.
Even though it is spoken about in the
Old Testament, but in the future,
because people don't understand that.
See, let me back up and make sure I I
say this. Why are you harping on this,
brother Jared? Because what Satan told
Eve is what people are still falling for
today. What did he tell Eve? You shall
not surely die.
So now when you go to a funeral, they
what do they say? That's not sister such
and such. They're not dead. She's made
her homecoming. In other words, they're
saying she's not dead. But the Bible
said
uh in the Garden of Eden, the day that
you eat thereof, you shall surely die.
So someone is saying that they're not
dead. They're floating off somewhere
else. They're in a better place. The
Bible says, "No, they're dead. I I got
rid of them because of whatever the
reason was." And then it says, "I'm
going to bring them back for whatever
the reason is because everyone has to be
resurrected."
>> Revelation 11, these are called the two
witnesses. The two witnesses, but people
focus on the prophecy of THE TWO
WITNESSES. OH, THEY MUST BE GREAT
PREACHERS. And they don't focus on the
Lord's going to show what's going to
happen with their body as a witness of
what really life is and what
resurrection is and what death is. their
bodies is a big witness against all this
creation that lies against uh basic
understanding of what the book says.
Revelation 11 and verse one. Go ahead.
>> And there was given me a reed like unto
a rod,
>> right?
>> And the angel stood saying, "Rise and
measure the temple of God."
>> Measure the temple of God. Go ahead.
>> And the altar and them that worship
therein.
>> Right. This temple that is speaking
about is going to be built by
Zerubbabel. But this hasn't happened
yet. Go ahead. But the court which is
without the temple
>> the court which is without the temple.
In other words, right now they got the
dome of the rockhuh uh over there uh uh
um on the temple mount. Go ahead.
>> Leave out and measure it not
>> and don't deal with that temple. Why is
that? Go ahead.
>> For it is given unto the Gentiles.
>> Because the Gentiles are going to want
to take over that temple.
>> It's going to be built by the
They're going to build the temple. Yes.
In our in our generation, in our days.
Because he said, "This generation shall
not pass through until all this is
fulfilled." They're going to build the
temple and then the Gentiles are going
to come from Rome and say, "We're taking
over this because we run Christianity.
We don't need the temple in Judaism no
more. We're the church." That's what
they going to do. That's why it says he
going to take away the daily animal
sacrifice.
>> Correct.
>> Go ahead.
>> And the holy city shall they tread
underfoot.
>> How long?
>> 40 and two months. And they are going to
call ha cause havoc on earth for three
and a half years,
42 months. Other places say a time and a
time and a dividing of time or 1,260
days. Three score. So it says that
they're going to have absolute rule of
this earth for three and a half years
before the Lord pays them back. Go
ahead. That's the end of verse three.
>> That's the end of verse two.
>> Two, I'm sorry. Go ahead. Keep going.
Give me three.
>> And I will give power to my two
witnesses. While they got that power, he
said, "I'm going to give power to my two
witnesses." Go ahead.
>> And they shall prophesy 1,23
score days.
>> There it is. He has a counterbalance.
So, they're going to have all this
power. They're going to have the
microphone. Everyone's going to follow
them. And then he says, "My two
witnesses are over here, and I'm going
to give them power. Go ahead."
>> Clothing in sackcloth.
>> But they not going to be dressed well.
They going to be clothed in sackcloth.
The other one's going to be dressed in
opulence, beautiful attire, white robes,
golden cups. They going to have all the
opulence. He said, "My people have a
sackloth on." Big clue. That's the end
of verse three.
>> That's the end of three.
>> Give me verse seven now. Go ahead.
>> And when they shall have finished their
testimony,
>> Uhhuh.
>> the beast that ascendeth out of the
bottomless pit shall make war against
them, and shall overcome them.
>> That's Western Europe. They come out the
bottomless pit. They refer to it now as
a European Union. No, everyone, no one's
thinking about them having an army right
now. They talk about Ukraine, Russia,
Gaza, but that's the beast coming out
the bottomless pit. They will finally
kill these two witnesses. Go ahead.
>> And kill them.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And their bodies And their dead bodies
>> And their dead bodies, go ahead.
>> Shall lie in the streets of the great
city which spiritually is called Sodom
and Egypt.
>> So the great city, what great city is
this? This is Jerusalem. But when
Vatican or Rome moves into Jerusalem,
it's given a different spiritual
nickname. Go ahead.
>> Where also our Lord was crucified.
>> Hit that verse from the top one more
time.
>> And their dead bodies shall lie in the
streets of the great city which
spiritually is called Sodom and Egypt.
>> There it is. Spiritually is now going to
be called Sodom and Egypt. Egyptians
worship the sun. In Sodom, they dealt
with man on man. I wonder why there's a
separate amount, a slush fund to pay
victims of Vatican abuse. Because that's
sodomy right there. He's letting you
know where it's at. They're just moving
from from Vatican to Jerusalem. So then
spiritually it will be sun worship and
sodomy. Go ahead.
>> Where also our Lord was crucified.
>> The same city which our Lord was
crucified which he's trying to let you
know that's going to be when the
Gentiles move in. They're bringing
lawlessness over there. That's the end
of that verse.
>> That's the end of eight.
>> Perfect. Jump now to verse 11. Because
they they were dead. their dead bodies
in the street for three days and a half.
Go ahead, give me verse 11 now. Go
ahead.
>> And after three days and a half, the
spirit of life from God entered into
them.
>> What? The what? From God,
>> the spirit of life. So now we see a
spirit entering into them. But we saw
the whole time that people that are
living receive breath. The spirit of
life from God entering into them. Go
ahead. And they stood upon their feet.
>> Hold up. Hold up. Hold up. And this is
where this is a big witness because if
you had a funeral for the two witnesses,
you would say they not here. They going
on somewhere else. That's just their
shell. Then why does the body stand up?
The body that they killed finally gets
up. That's what how you know. Well, then
we must not know what a soul is cuz I
thought that their soul went somewhere
else. Then why is the body that we just
desecrated after killing coming back to
life? Yeah.
>> See, people don't even
Yeah. No. No. I don't I don't need to go
that deep. Go ahead. I I'mma say
something for later. Go ahead.
>> And great fear fell upon them which saw
them.
>> RIGHT. CUZ NOW THEY'RE SCARED that cuz
they see people they killed come back to
life. And if they knew who the two
witnesses look like, they really going
to be scared. Hold up. We can't kill
them
because they now stand up for life. The
Lord has resurrected them at that time.
This is This hasn't even happened yet.
We don't even know who the two witnesses
are, but the two witnesses are alive
right now. We don't know who they are,
but they are alive. And they're going to
be two Israelites because they're called
natural branches, not graft in branches,
>> right? So, there's going to be two
Israelites that the world's going to
hate and kill according to this book.
But that's the end of verse 11, right?
>> That's the end of of 11.
>> Perfect. Let's go to Job 33.
Job 33.
So what do you do with your explanation
of what death and resurrection is when
the two witnesses come? Because now you
have to acknowledge what is raised is an
actual body. When Jesus came out the
grave, they didn't say, "Woo! T been
resurrected." He just left his shell
back there in the grave site. They said
the tomb was empty.
That's why when I do funerals, I tell
them during this eulogy, I'm going to
have to explain to you what death is
because a lot of people don't even know
what death is. So, I can encourage you
about the resurrection. But if you think
that
death is something different, then when
I speak about the resurrection of the
body, you don't know what to do with
that.
So, I have to teach people sometimes
during their grief.
Job 33 and verse one. Job 33 and verse
one. Like I said, this is a corrective
lesson, but you get this piece corrected
and then next week we'll correct
something else and something else.
Before you know it, this book is like
it's like the cheat code. All of a
sudden, I I can see so many things I
couldn't see before. All these questions
are now answered.
Job 33 and verse one. When you get
there, go ahead and read.
>> Wherefore, Job, I pray thee, hear my
speeches, right? and hearken to all my
words.
>> Right.
>> Behold, now I have opened my mouth. My
tongue have spoken in my mouth.
>> Uh-huh.
>> My word shall be of the uprightness of
my heart.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And my lips shall utter knowledge
clearly.
>> Uh-huh.
>> The spirit of God hath made me.
>> The spirit of God has made me. Go ahead.
>> And the breath of the Almighty have
given me life.
>> Now, they don't Now, they really don't
know what to do with this verse four.
What does it mean? The spirit of God has
made me. When God was going through the
creation, he said, "Let there be. Let
there be. Let there be. And then an
angel would obey the commandment that
God gave the angel because God was
talking to the father. You know, we
should make man in our image. And then
the angel would do exactly what God told
him to do. So this spirit here that made
him is an angel at the direction of God.
Go ahead. It said and the breath of the
almighty. It didn't say the breath of
the angel, did it? The breath of the
almighty hath given me life. So after he
the angel formed exactly what God told
him to form, then God breathed into
their nostrils the breath of life. Go
ahead, give me verse five.
>> If thou can't answer me, set thy words
in order before me. Stand up.
>> Behold, I am according to thy wish in
God'sstead.
>> Uh-huh.
>> I also am formed out of the clay.
>> I'm also formed out of the what?
>> Clay.
>> That's another way of saying the dirt.
I'm formed out of the clay. Go ahead.
Behold, my terror shall not make thee
afraid, neither shall my hand be heavy
upon thee.
>> Jump down to verse 14. Go ahead.
>> For God speaketh once, yay, twice, yet
man perceiveth not.
>> In other words, sometimes the Lord
trying to get someone some information,
but they don't catch it right away.
>> He speaks to them once, sometimes he
warns them twice,
>> but man don't perceive. They go about
their business. Go ahead.
>> In a dream.
>> Sometimes in a dream. Go ahead.
>> In a vision of of the night.
>> Uh-huh. When deep sleep fallth upon men,
>> right,
>> and slumberings upon the bed,
>> sometimes he'll give you information or
give you like he gave to Joseph, take
this child and flee into Egypt because
Herod will seek to destroy the child.
Right.
>> Right.
>> Or like I think it was Aimilec that the
Lord said unto him, you a dead man cuz
the woman that you have is a man's wife.
He said, I didn't know that. Didn't he
say that that was his sister? So the
Lord is reproving him while he sleep.
Because the Lord sometimes because when
the Lord want to come in, you can't
stop. That's the crazy part people don't
realize yet. Go ahead.
>> Then he openeth the ears of men.
>> Then he opens your ears. Go ahead.
>> And sealth their instruction.
>> And seals their instruction. Even after
Solomon had dedicated the first temple
unto God, God came unto him in his
dreams and had a whole conversation with
him. Yeah, I heard your prayer. Yeah. If
my people will humble themselves, the my
people which are called by my name will
humble themselves and seek my face, then
will I hear their prayer and heal their
land. That was all said in his dreams,
>> right?
>> Go ahead.
>> That he may withdraw man from his
purpose and hide pride from man.
>> And sometimes he's letting them know you
kicking against the wrong person that
you don't realize. Paul didn't realize
who he's kicking against until the Lord
knocked him off that high horse. So he
said he's trying to withdraw you from
your purpose. Like uhoh, you need to
slow down now. You don't know who you
kicking against. Go ahead.
>> He keep it back his soul from the pit.
>> He keepeth back his what?
>> Soul.
>> His soul from the pit. In other words,
his soul from the grave. In other words,
I'm trying to keep you alive so you
don't have to die. Soul from the pit. Go
ahead.
>> And his life from perishing by the
sword.
sword. This doesn't mean sword like like
a weapon. This talking about the sword
of the Lord when the Lord wants to do
something. Because sometimes people fall
by many different means. That's the end
of verse uh 18.
>> That is the end of 18.
>> Okay, perfect. Give me 19.
>> He is casting also with pain upon his
bed.
>> Sometimes someone has sickness or cancer
like we just went uh recently this past
week visit someone in the hospital. I'm
going room by room by room and they all
laid up on their bed suffering with
pain. Sometimes he's doing that to get
your attention. Go ahead. and the
multitude of his bones with strong pain
>> and multitude of his bones with strong
pain. It talks about how hey he they
were wellfed then all of a sudden once
that disease set in the bones that you
couldn't see now stick out. Sometimes it
happens that way. Sometimes he's trying
to get someone else's attention by the
sickness of this one person because I
can't say the 12-year-old did something
wrong then that's why she had died. I
can't say that. But I know one thing,
when the Lord did that miracle, a lot of
people that was around that woman was
like, "Oh, this guy's the real deal."
>> Sometimes he's using it as a tool
>> for other people. Just, in other words,
just be receptive when the Lord is
knocking on your door. That's all I'm
saying. That's the end of verse 19.
>> Yes, that's the end of 19.
>> All right, let's go to Ezekiel 18. And I
want to uh I want to ask I want to ask a
simple question concerning what a soul
is because I still want to make sure
that I iron this down. Can a soul die?
>> Yes.
>> See, y'all cheating. Y'all been here a
while.
>> Y'all been reading the Bible already.
Before I came into the Israelite guy, I
already said, "No, of course a soul
can't die." What are you? That's
preposterous.
Of course they can't die until you read
the Bible. Let's see what the Bible says
if a soul can die.
>> Ezekiel chapter 18.
>> Did you want to skip over the Psalms?
>> Oh. Uh uh. Hold on. Hold on.
>> Psalms 33.
>> You know what?
Let's do that. No, let me give you Psalm
33. Thank you for that. What threw me
off is we came from Job 33 and I saw
that 33 and I jump to the next verse.
Let let me hit Psalm 33 and then we'll
go directly to Ezekiel 18. Psalm 33
and we'll pick it up at verse 13.
Psalm 33.
Thank you for that. Which is another
reason why y'all don't trust in the
flesh because I make mistakes.
But even if I make a mistake, the Bible
still says what it says. So he can
always reprove me. Jerry, it didn't say
that. It said this.
>> See that?
>> We're showing real time that this thing
is is uh is fail proof. Ezekiel 18
Psalm 33. I know sometimes I watch
Brother Buoie and I see how he'll make
that mistake and it's like I get it now
because because when you're trying to
explain something to someone, you have
so many different things that you're
thinking of, I could I need to show
this, I need to explain that. And your
mind is like moving like two, three
steps ahead. So sometimes you're ahead
than where you are right now. And I get
it, man. I get it. He's Psalm 33.
I also see I remember one time I was
reading for him. I was reading for
brother Buie some years ago. Right.
>> Right.
>> And I saw that he put a ruler under the
verse he's dealing with so he doesn't
look ahead too. So I said, "Oh, I need
to I need to do that. I got a ruler. I
just keep forgetting to do that cuz I
mean I'll be watching some things that
buoy doesn't like, oh man, that's that.
I like how he did that." You know,
Psalm 33 and 13. Go ahead.
>> The Lord lookth from heaven. He
beholdeth all the sons of men. Uh-huh.
He looking at everybody. Go ahead.
>> From the place of his habitation, he
looked upon all the inhabitants of the
earth.
>> Uh-huh.
>> He fashioned their hearts alike.
>> Right. Consider all their works.
>> He's watching all their works. Go ahead.
>> There is no king saved by the multitude
of in host. A mighty man is not
delivered by much strength.
>> Uh-huh. In other words, they can't
deliver their they can't believe their
army all the way because the Lord's
really controlling the battlefield.
That's why, you know, so we over there
messing with Iran and we ain't we ain't
winning nothing, are we? Because he
trusted too much in his hopes. Go ahead.
>> And horse is a vain thing for safety.
>> And that's and hope is a vain thing. Go
ahead.
>> Neither shall
>> Oh, you said horse is a vain thing for
safety. Yep. Go ahead.
>> Neither shall he deliver any by his
great strength.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Behold, the eye of the Lord is upon them
that fear him,
>> upon them that hope in his mercy. And
the people that's living right, that
fear him and hoping in his mercy, he's
like his eyes upon them. In other words,
he got his angels watching them and
keeping them in line, too. Go ahead.
>> To deliver their soul
>> to deliver their what?
>> soul.
>> Go ahead.
>> From death and to keep them alive in
famine.
>> And even when a family hits, they going
to be kept alive. Why? Because they this
angel's working when either God directs
it to keep their soul from death. Cuz a
soul can die. But we're going to see
this. That's why I kind of had asked the
question, can a soul die?
>> Correct? So now the Lord is doing all
this to stop a soul from dying that he
wants to live. Let's go now to Ezekiel
18 now
and pick it up at verse one. Ezekiel 18
and verse one.
Now we're going to ask, well then can a
soul actually die? Because according to
the Hollywood movie that I saw, I saw
this that and the other. In fact, what
was the name of that movie? I think it
was a Pixar movie. They named a movie
called Soul.
Oh my goodness.
[sighs]
And you talk about flipping the Bible
upside down. That's exactly what they
did. They said, "Oh, well, see, you were
in heaven as a soul and then you came
from heaven and dropped down into a body
and that determines your gender."
That's what they were trying to They're
trying to say, "Well, see, I'm this on
the outside, but on the inside, I'm
really something else." That's
confusion,
>> right?
>> Madness.
Take a look after this lesson. Go watch
that movie and watch how deceptive Satan
is. Ezekiel 18 and verse one. When you
get there, go ahead and read. The word
of the Lord came came unto me again,
saying,
>> "Right,
>> what mean ye that ye use this proverb
concerning the land of Israel, saying,
>> the fathers have eaten sour grapes, and
the children's teeth are set on edge?"
>> Uhhuh.
>> "As I live, sayith the Lord God, ye
shall not have occasion anymore to use
this proverb in Israel."
>> You say, "Look, you ain't even gonna use
this proverb anymore because now it's
going to be everyone individual on how
they individually behave." Go ahead.
Behold, all souls are mine.
>> Behold, all souls are mine. Go ahead.
>> As the soul of the father,
>> right?
>> So also the soul of the son,
>> the father's soul and the son's soul. Go
ahead.
>> The soul that sinnth.
>> The soul that sins, go ahead,
>> it shall die.
>> Now God can't be lying then, can he?
Didn't he just say the soul that sins
shall do what?
>> Die.
>> Die. The soul that sin shall So can a
soul die?
>> Yes. Because God don't lie, right? Man
lies. God don't. Go ahead. That's the
end of verse four.
>> That's the end of four.
>> Jump down to verse 19. Verse 19. Like I
said, we're just trying to hit some
simple stuff, but it's really not simple
if you've never dealt with it. 19.
>> Yet say ye, why do not the son bear the
iniquity of the father?
>> Right?
>> When the son have done that which is
lawful and right? But he said, "Hey,
when the son has done that which is
lawful or they were obedient, go ahead.
>> And have kept all my statutes
>> and had kept all my statutes." Go ahead.
>> And have done them.
>> And have done them. Go ahead.
>> He shall surely live.
>> God said he shall surely live. That does
now see what they don't realize. This
live here is talking about you shall not
go into the second death because
everyone goes through that first death
thing. But then during the resurrection,
you don't have to go to the lake of
fire, which the Bible calls the second
death. He shall surely live. They going
to inherit the kingdom. Go ahead.
>> The soul that sinnth,
>> the soul that sins though, go ahead.
>> It shall die.
>> It shall die. And if God is able to uh
destroy an angel, an angel of spirit,
then what you think he could do with a
soul? He could take that down too
easily. Go ahead. The son shall not bear
the the iniquity of the father.
>> That's right.
>> Neither shall the father bear the
iniquity of the son.
>> Right.
>> The righteousness of the righteous shall
be upon him.
>> Right.
>> And the wickedness of the wicked shall
be upon him.
>> So if you righteous, then let them be
righteous still. If you unclean or
wicked, his the book says, "Let them be
unclean still cuz the Lord going to give
everyone according to their works." So
that's what we see here. Everybody got
to report on their own works on judgment
day. But it says the soul that sins it
shall die. But this is the thing,
brother Jared. We all have sinned and
fell short of the glory of God.
Absolutely. And that's why we all have
Jesus Christ as our advocate or our
propitiation by coming under his blood.
But when you come under his blood, that
doesn't mean now I could break all the
laws cuz I said I'm under Jesus blood.
No, that doesn't work that way either.
You will invalidate your uh uh your
pardon. You will invalidate it. That's
why it says uh uh the person that says
my lord delayed his coming and he start
abusing people and everything and
mistreating people he said the original
payment that uh I have forgave him for
is GOING TO COME BACK on him. That's why
when you come under the blood your your
sins are in remission.
In other words, it could come back on
you if you start misbehaving.
>> Just like your cancer can come out of
remission. It come right back on you.
That's why someone can have their name
in the book of life. Well, I'm once
saved, always saved, brother Jared, then
how can this name can GET BLOTTED OUT?
NO ONE'S THINKING.
Nobody is thinking. It's amazing me. But
let's go to James chapter 5. James
chapter 5. Everybody knows in all all
these other walks of life that if you
stop applying yourself, this thing will
drop. If you stop maintaining your car,
guess what? Your car is going to break
down.
athletes, tell them stop working out and
they're not going to finish the season
and they aren't going to win a
championship. A track star is not going
to cross the finish line if he says,
"Well, I made it 3/4 of the way. Now I
can slow up." Come on now. If this
I can stop showing my wife love cuz we
got married some years ago. What does
that mean? Come on now. That don't mean
I get to now say, "Well, I have to show
you no love no more." know I still
surprise her with flowers and stuff from
time to time. I still was like saying
sweet nothing's in her ear. I like to
keep it fresh.
>> So then how when it comes to the word of
God, I don't have to keep this fresh
with him because you know I got baptized
so many years ago and I don't touch my
Bible. My Bible has so much dust on the
back of it that if I blew it, you
thought I was going on the back of a
fan.
>> But I thought I was right with God, but
I didn't open the book. That's why it
says it's like the scribe has written it
in vain. He has all this writing for
nothing because you ain't reading it.
He's saying
James chapter five. James five. That's
why when you learn and you start getting
yourself together, you are now in
position to help someone else get their
yourself together. Because just the same
way that if I say, "Man, this restaurant
has some excellent food." Right.
>> The the yams, the mac and cheese, the
green beans, whatever it is, now it's
word of mouth. Right.
>> Right. Oh, you got to try this over on
14 and K Northwest that you do all that
to share that word. Right.
>> Right.
>> Then what about this? And this the bread
that you ain't even going hunger for no
more. You could hunger for that regular
bread, but until about four, six hours
later, you going to be looking for
something else, right?
>> So, this is same thing. Word of mouth.
You help someone else, the Lord gives a
uh uh it's almost like a referral fee.
He's like, "Okay, because you did that,
it says when you turn a um a a sinner
from the transgression of their ways,
you shall hold them hide a multitude of
sins."
James chapter 5 and verse 19. 5 and 19.
Go ahead. Brethren, if any of you do
heir from the truth
>> and one convert him, let him know that
he
>> So, someone made a mistake and someone
corrects or converts them. That That's
what that is, a correction. Go ahead.
>> Let him know that he which convertth the
sinner from
>> the one that converted the sinner, Go
ahead.
>> From the error of his way,
>> right,
>> shall save a soul from death.
>> See, you shall save a soul from what?
>> Death. Because if they continue in that
sin, the soul shall die.
>> But if you convert them, tell them,
"Actually, brother, the Bible didn't
tell us to go to church on Sunday. It
told us go keep the Sabbath day." He
said, "Remember the Sabbath day, keep it
holy." He said, "We even going to keep
this in his kingdom." So when I convert
one, it's what did it say that I'm going
to do? I'm going to save a soul from
what?
>> Death.
>> Go ahead.
>> And shall hide a multitude of sin.
>> And a whole lot of dirt that I got on my
record, I could get some of that looked
over. So, I'm trying to recruit
everybody because I got a large record.
>> But that's what we seeing here. And
guess what? They gonna try to do the
same thing. Someone else, hey, I made
some mistakes over here. Okay, come. You
learn how to do right and just spread it
on. And Lord going to look over some
stuff in your record and it keeps going
that way. This isn't just about someone
sitting in a seat. It's about also your
record being expuned. Let's go now to
Hebrews 10. Why am I saying that?
Because just because you come into the
word and do right, doesn't mean that the
Lord ain't going to get some strikes up
off you from all the time where you was
wrong. He's still going to collect. It
may not be as much, but he's still going
to uh uh rattle your cage a little bit
to en ensure which side you on. Cuz some
people say I'm on the lower side, but
then
Sunday through Friday, they show they on
someone else's side.
Hebrews chapter 10. Hebrews chapter 10.
So when you converse someone, you have
helped them stop digging themselves in a
ditch deeper and deeper and deeper.
Someone uh you know, you go on a cruise
ship, someone falls overboard, you throw
them a life raft, right?
>> Right.
>> And they like, "You know what? Because
you helped rescue this person, I'm going
to discount your uh your room rate. I'm
going to take this off. Don't worry
about this. Don't worry about that." And
that's all it is. That's all it is.
Because none of us can pay what the real
penalty is because the wages of sin is
what?
>> Death.
>> That's what the real penalty of. And
none of us can pay that full price.
That's why Jesus paid it for us. So
because Jesus paid it for us, I'm going
to let people know about the program
that Jesus put on the table, which is
baptism in his name, and then also walk
in newness of life. So if I was pagan
before and I come under Jesus blood, I
can't go back to paganism, can I? Nope.
But someone says, "Well, I got Jesus
blood, so now I can keep Christmas." No,
that's paganism. The Bible, he I can
read what Jesus tells us. Don't do that.
But he said people don't listen to him.
Hebrews 10 and1. 10 and1. When you get
there, go ahead and read.
>> For the law having a shadow of good
things to come and not the very image of
the things.
>> See, brother Jared, you keeping that
law. You under the law. I'm under grace.
But they don't know what law PAUL'S
TALKING ABOUT.
IT SAYS, "FOR the law HAVING A SHADOW OF
GOOD THINGS TO COME." Go ahead.
>> And not the very image of the things.
I'm using a red heer. I'm using a lamb.
I'm using goats to represent THE ONE
WHO'S GOING to Christ going to come,
which is Christ. In other words, that's
the one that was supposed to come. Go
ahead.
>> Can never WITH THOSE SACRIFICES.
>> OH, THIS IS what he's talking about.
animal sacrifice.
Not about keeping the dietary law, not
about the Sabbath day. This is all about
the law. Animal sacrifice. The Bible
says the law that was added because of
sins. Go ahead.
>> Which they offered year by year,
continually making the comers to their
unto perfect.
>> Right? No matter how many animals you
killed, you cannot become perfect by
killing animals. Cuz animals didn't
really commit sin. It was man that did
that. Go ahead, jump down to verse four.
Go ahead.
>> For it is not possible that the blood of
bulls and and and of goats shall take
away his to take away sin
>> because it's impossible for animal blood
to take away sin. That's why we have
substituted animal blood for Jesus blood
because Jesus was a sin offering
according to the Old Testament. That's
why a lot of things happened in a
particular way because he was a sin
offering. Go ahead. Verse five. Where
wherefore when he cometh into the world,
right, he says, "Sacrifice and offering
thou wouldest not, but a body hast thou
prepared me?"
>> Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Sacrifice and
offering. Lord didn't want animal
sacrifice, but a what have you prepared
me?
>> A body.
>> Hold up. Now, I need to see this. So,
the body that was prepared, where did it
go? Was he crucified?
>> He was on the cross, right?
>> A body has thou prepared me? Go ahead.
and burnt offerings and sacrifices for
sin. Thou has had no pleasure.
>> Right? Because those sacrifices
represent disobedience. You have to get
a sacrifice because you broke the
Sabbath day because you broke the
dietary law because you didn't keep the
feast days. Whatever it was, now you
have to bring an animal. He said, I
didn't care about the animal part.
That's the makeup homework. Go ahead.
>> Then said I, Lo, I come in the
[clears throat] volume of the book,
>> right?
>> It is written of me to do thy will, oh
God.
>> Right. Go ahead. above when he said,
"Sacrifice and offering and the burnt
offerings and offering for sin, thou
wouldest not, right?
>> Neither hast pleasured therein."
>> You didn't have pleasure in in those uh
uh sacrifices. Go ahead.
>> Which are offered by the law.
>> Uh-huh. The the which law? The law of
animal sacrifice.
>> Like I said, I get it cuz in our
neighborhood, we have a lot of people
that abbreviate stuff. Paul does a lot
of abbreviating. And that abbreviation
calls the Gentiles to mix them up and
not know what he's talking about. So he
said, "You g you going to go to the law
before the law before the unjust because
someone owes you $20." No, he should
have just said court system. You going
to go on Judge Judy because someone owes
you money versus handling that inside
the church. That's what he's saying. But
because they don't know how Paul
abbreviates it, throws them off. Go
ahead.
>> Then said he.
>> What verse we at?
>> Nine.
>> Nine. Go ahead. Then said he, "Lo, I
come to to do the will of oh God.
>> I come to do thy will." Go ahead.
>> He taketh away the first, right?
>> That he may establish the second.
>> You're right. He takes away the first
law of animal sacrifice to establish the
new covenant. Go ahead.
>> By the which will we are sanctified
through the offering of the body of
Jesus Christ once for all.
>> Hold up. We are sanctified through the
offering of the what?
>> BODY. BODY of Jesus Christ once and for
all through the offering of Jesus
Christ's body. Now that we see that,
let's go now to Isaiah 53
because Jesus had a soul also.
And let's go read about it in Isaiah
chapter 53.
And we going to pick it up at verse one.
Isaiah 53 and verse one. That's what m
this Bible is so simple. If you get
yourself out the way, the Bible is very
simple. When you get out the way, you
make you you mess up the recipe. And now
it's so complex that no one can solve
it. Now we have one GOSPEL AND 50,000
DENOMINATIONS CUZ man keeps getting in
the way of his word.
Well, I'm Presbyterian. Well, I'm Church
of God in Christ. Well, I'm Roman
Catholic. Well, I'm Baptist. I'm
Methodist. I'm Mormon. I'm Seventh Day
Adventist. I'm all these things except
what the Bible calls the New Testament
church, the Israel of God.
But I can't just say the Gentiles got in
the way because some of Israelites got
in the way, too. But we're going now to
Isaiah 53 and we going to pick it up at
verse one.
That's why people say, "Well, you don't
ever talk two things, politics and
religion." Well, we're here in DC, so
it's going to be some type of politics
talked about somewhere,
>> right?
>> But the reason why people don't want to
talk about religion because they like,
"We can't figure it out either." They
think that this is the sword from the
stone that no one CAN PULL FROM. NO ONE
CAN MAKE SENSE OF IT. WHO CAN read the
handwriting ON THE WALL? NOBODY CAN. NO,
they just think about themselves. They
never come to ask us. The people that
are the children of Israel who always
give the answers. All the prophets, all
the disciples, all the writers of the
New Testament, all were Israelites.
And they never come to us first. They
come to us last. That's why he said, "I
remember my thoughts this day. I should
have holl at Joseph. There was this
Hebrew that was locked UP WITH ME. HE
HAS THE ANSWERS. But they only when it
benefits them come to us
>> before then they do their thing.
>> So you could be in the desert for two
years. They ain't gonna think nothing
about you until it's time for someone to
give the understanding.
>> Isaiah 53 and verse one. Go ahead. Who
hath believed our report?
>> Now the question is asked, who's
believed our report? They believed
everyone else's report. Who's believed
our report? Go ahead.
>> And to whom is the arm of the Lord
revealed? To whom has the arm of the
Lord representing Jesus been revealed?
Go ahead.
>> For he shall go grow up before him as a
tender plant.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And as a root out of the dry ground.
>> That's right.
>> He have no form, no calmness.
>> He had no form, no what?
>> Nor calmliness.
>> Comeliness is saying he didn't come to
look like a pretty boy.
But they don't believe our report cuz
they said, well, you know, Mel Gibson
got a new movie coming out. It's the
It's another resurrection film and they
got another pretty boy playing Jesus.
That's not our report. That's someone
else's report that you putting out there
because we could show his hair type. We
could show the color of his skin. We
could show all these things, but they
don't want to believe it because they
get themselves in the way of the
scriptures.
>> Right.
>> Go ahead.
>> And when we shall see him,
>> when we see him, go ahead.
>> There is no beauty.
>> There is some beauty. There is NO
>> THERE'S A LOT OF BEAUTY.
>> NO,
>> no beauty. Go ahead.
>> That we should desire him.
>> So why do I see everyone pining over
these pictures? Oh, it's such a handsome
actor playing Jesus Christ.
>> Cuz they don't want to believe our
report. Our report going to say he's not
going to LOOK TOO GOOD. NO BEAUTY. Go
ahead.
>> He is despised and rejected again.
>> And he is going to be despised and
rejected. Go ahead. a man of sorrows,
>> right?
>> And acquainted with grief,
>> and he gonna have a lot of grief. Go
ahead.
>> And we hid as it were our faces from
him.
>> And it's like we turn our back on him.
Go ahead.
>> He was despised and we esteemed him not.
>> And they still don't esteem him. Go
ahead. The real him. Not not the not the
scarecrow, the other one. The one that
they replace him with. No, the real one
they don't esteem. Go ahead.
>> Surely he he have borne our grief.
>> But he's CARRIED OUR GRIEFS. GO AHEAD.
and carried our sorrows.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Yet we did esteem him stricken.
>> But we said he going through this
suffering on the cross because God's
upset at him. That's what we thought in
our head. He said, "Go ahead."
>> Smitten of God and
>> afflicted.
>> He's been smitten. God is smitting him
and afflicting him. Go ahead.
>> But he was wounded for our
transgressions.
>> But he's being wounded for our
transgressions. Go ahead.
>> He was bruised for our iniquities.
>> He's bruised for our iniquities. Go
ahead. The chastisement of our peace was
upon him.
>> He's jumping in front of the BULLET TO
PROTECT US. GO AHEAD.
>> And with his stripes we are healed.
>> AND BY HIS STRIPES WE have a chance to
get healed. Go ahead. Give me first six.
>> All we like SHEEP HAVE GONE ASTRAY.
>> SOME OF US,
>> all everybody has sinned and fell short
of the glory of God. That's why we know
we need an advocate.
We know that we have some errors that we
need to have an eraser to clean up those
mistakes. But after I CLEAN UP THAT
MISTAKE, I DON'T GO AND WRITE MORE
MISTAKES, DO I?
OH, we like sheep have gone astray. Go
ahead. We have turned everyone to his
own way.
>> Now, everyone goes in their own ways.
Like I said, you turn Roman Catholic.
You turn Methodist. You They going their
own ways. Go ahead. And the Lord hath
laid on him the iniquity of us all.
>> And on him was laid the iniquity of us
all. How do we know this? Verse 10. Go
ahead.
>> Verse 10. Yet it pleased the Lord to
bruise him.
>> But it pleased the father to bruise him.
Go ahead.
>> He have put him to grief.
>> He been the father HAS PUT HIM TO GRIEF.
GO AHEAD.
>> When when thou shalt make his soul an
offering FOR SIN.
>> WHOA. WHOA. NO. HIS BODY AN OFFERING FOR
SIN.
>> His soul an offering for sin.
>> So what was on the cross which we called
a body in Hebrews chapter 10, we now
know we can call it a soul. When he made
his soul an offering for sin,
finish it out.
>> He shall see his seed.
>> Uhhuh.
>> He shall prolong his days,
>> but he going to be resurrected. In other
words, he's going to have more life.
Prolong his days. Go ahead. and the
pleasure of the Lord shall prosper in
his hand.
>> And the Lord going to use him to correct
the whole earth. The father is going to
use Jesus to do all of this even though
his soul was made an offering for sin.
So if his soul was made an offering for
sin on the cross or his body was made
that offering, then let's see what well
then what was put in the grave then? May
maybe that'll clear it up. If I can find
out what WENT IN THE GRAVE, IT WILL
ANSWER all these QUESTIONS AND MAKE IT
CLEAR. Psalm 16.
Psalms chapter 16.
All this understanding has been hidden
from the world until the last days. And
knock knock, here we are. Whether you
believe it or not, you are in the last
days.
You could look at everything going on in
this society and say, "Yep, I'mma just
start checking things off of Revelation.
this that that but he said that the the
the Pharisees they could discern the
weather to understand oh it might rain
later today right but she said you can't
discern the signs of the times it's so
many signs out right here right uh going
on right now and they aren't discerning
which is means that their congregation
is not being warned about what's about
to happen which means when you get ready
for an accident you have no chance to
brace for impact because he said I come
as a thief
Watch and pray. Psalm 16 and verse one.
When you get there, go ahead and read.
>> Preserve me.
>> Preserve me. Uh-huh.
>> Oh God. For in in thee in indeed do I
put my trust.
>> So we're seeing Jesus talking in the Old
Testament asking to be preserved. Go
ahead.
>> Oh my soul, thou hast said unto the
Lord, thou art my Lord. My goodness
extendeth not to thee.
>> He said, Oh my soul. He said this is not
for the father. He said my goodness, all
this good that he doing is not for the
father. Go ahead.
>> But to the saints that are in the earth.
The father committed no sin. He doesn't
need a propitiation. The saints in the
earth do. So the blood COVERS US. IT
DOESN'T COVER THE FATHER. That's why he
said, "My goodness extended not unto
thee, but to the saints that are in the
earth." Go ahead.
>> And to the excellent in whom is all by
delay. to the excellent
in WHOM IS ALL MY DELIGHT.
That excellent just like you saw it said
Daniel had AN EXCELLENT SPIRIT BUT HE
wasn't breaking God's commandments.
That's how you get excellence. Go ahead.
That's the end of verse three.
>> That's the end of three.
>> I want four as well. Go ahead.
>> Verse four. Their sorrows shall be
multiplied.
>> But the people that don't want to
listen, he said, I'mma multiply their
sorrows. Go ahead.
>> That has hashen after another god. Those
that follow after other gods, he said,
"Especially them." Go ahead.
>> Their drink offerings of blood will I
not offer.
>> I will not even call their name when uh
when it's time to cover them with my
blood for the Passover. He said, "Their
drink offerings of blood will I not
offer." Go ahead.
>> Nor take up their names into my lips.
>> Why? Why? Because the name's blotted
out. So what good is to call a name IF I
CAN'T SEE IT? WHY? Cuz they hate for
another God, not the true and living
God. In other words, they use my name
and throw paganism under it. Now, jump
down to verse eight. Go ahead.
>> I have set the Lord always before me
because he is at my right hand.
>> Uhhuh.
>> I shall not be moved.
>> I shall not be moved. Go ahead.
>> Therefore, my heart is glad.
>> And my glory rejoicth.
>> Uh-huh.
>> My flesh also shall rest in hope.
>> My flesh
also shall rest in the hope.
Flesh is referring to a body. So where
did it rest? It rested in the grave.
So he said, "My flesh shall rest in
hope." Right.
>> Right.
>> Go ahead.
>> For thou would not leave my soul in
hell.
>> Hold up. Cuz you won't leave my what?
>> My soul.
>> YOU WON'T LEAVE MY SOUL IN HELL. HELL
MEANS SH meaning the grave. You will not
leave my body in the grave. Why is that?
Go ahead.
>> Neither wil thou suffer thy holy one to
seek corruption
>> because corruption or we'll say de uh uh
decomposition
corrosion. All this happens to a body.
But he say you won't leave my soul in
hell. Neither will thou suffer thy holy
want to see corruption. Even though my
flesh shall rest in hope. This is all
concerning the grave site where Jesus
was buried in the garden of Gethsemane.
Do y'all see this?
>> Yes, sir.
Like I said, it's everywhere, but it's
nowhere if you don't understand it.
Let's go now to uh uh that was the end
of verse 10. That was the end of 10.
>> Perfect. Let's go now New Testament.
Let's go to Acts chapter 2.
Let's see if we just kind of pulled that
from nowhere or we just grabbed a a
outlier and try to establish that. We
don't do that. We keep reading here. And
that's why when I started this lesson in
Matthew chapter 10, I showed Matthew's
perspective, then I show Luke's
perspective to understand which one
heard it correctly.
And we've been going through all
afternoon rectifying and and seeing that
Luke heard it right, not Matthew.
That's why it says two or three
witnesses, let a factor of matter be
established. Paul even had to uh uh
correct one of the churches because they
weren't doing that. said this this is
the second or third time I'm coming to
you that in the mouth of two or three
witnesses let it be established
Acts chapter 2 and verse 22 this is the
day of Pentecost which is tomorrow that
we still keep
Pentecost just means 50
and how do you get to Pentecost you have
to go through seven Sabbaths 7 * 7 is 49
and then the very next day 49 + 1 equals
50. So after Jesus died, they were doing
what we still do today, which means the
day before this in Acts chapter 2, they
all had to be together. That's why you
go read Acts chapter 1
because Pentecost always comes on a
Sunday after the weekly Sabbath.
Acts chapter 2 and 22. When you get
there, go ahead and read. Ye men of
Israel,
>> you men of Israel, go ahead.
>> Hear these words.
>> Right.
>> Jesus of Nazareth, a man approved of God
among you by miracles and wonders and
signs which God did by him in the midst
of you.
>> Right.
>> As ye yourselves also know.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Him being delivered by the determined
counsel.
>> The determined council. In other words,
they had already made an agreement
before mankind was made that if they
were to fall, someone would go down and
rescue them. So the determinant council,
go ahead.
>> And for knowledge of God,
>> and for knowledge of God, go ahead.
>> Ye have taken and by wicked hands have
crucified and slain.
>> You have killed him, but you were
fulfilling prophecy and didn't even
realize it. Go ahead.
>> Whom God have raised up.
>> God has raised up. Go ahead.
>> Having loosed the pains of death,
>> right?
>> Because it was not possible that he
should be holding of it.
>> Because it's not possible to keep him in
the grave. Go ahead. For David speaketh
concerning him.
>> Cuz David speak concerning him. Go
ahead.
>> I foraw the Lord always before my face.
For he is on my right hand
>> that I should not be moved.
>> That's right. Go ahead.
>> Therefore did my heart rejoice and my
tongue was glad.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Moreover also my flesh shall rest in
hope.
>> There it is. Now he's quoting what we
read in Psalm 16. He's,
how can I say, teaching all these
Hebrews from the Hebraic scriptures and
showing who it's talking about. Go
ahead.
>> Because thou will not leave my soul in
hell.
>> Because you will not leave my soul in
hell. Go ahead.
>> Neither wilth I suffer thy holy one to
see corruption.
>> Didn't we just read that together?
>> Yep.
>> Let's see who was talking about. Give me
verse 29. Go ahead.
>> Men and brethren.
>> Men and brethren. Go ahead. Let me
freely speak unto you of the patriarch
David.
>> Let me speak plainly about King David.
Go ahead.
>> That he is both dead and buried.
>> He's still dead and he's still buried.
Go ahead.
>> And his supplr is with us until this
day.
>> AND HIS BURYING SPOT IS STILL HERE IN
Jerusalem with us until this very day.
Go ahead.
Therefore, being a prophet and knowing
that God has sworn with an oath to him
that of the fruits of his loins
according to the flesh,
>> the fruit of his loins according to his
flesh. Go ahead.
>> He would raise up Christ to sit on his
throne.
>> He would RAISE UP JESUS CHRIST to sit on
the throne of David to sit on his
throne. Now, why is this significant?
They are really listening to these
disciples because after Jesus
resurrected from the grave, it said many
of the saints came out of the graves and
appeared unto many. They were clear that
that resurrection is real because there
was a whole lot of raised saints around
in Jerusalem. So now when he says this
verse that you're reading in Psalm 16 is
not about David cuz David hadn't been
resurrected yet even though you seen all
these other people have been. In other
words, this is not about David. THIS IS
ABOUT JESUS CHRIST. THAT'S WHAT HE'S
TRYING TO LET THE JEWS KNOW. THAT'S WHY
YOU CANNOT CONVERT PEOPLE THAT ARE JEWS
IF YOU DON'T KNOW THE SCRIPTURES. YOU
HAVE TO GO TO THE SCRIPTURES AND EXPOUND
unto them what it's really talking
about. But that job is always given to
Israel because the Jews are Israelites.
Not all Israelites are Jews. Only one
tribe is Jews. That's the tribe of
Judah. But you know
who believed our report?
What verse we at?
>> Top of 31.
>> Uh-huh. Go ahead.
>> He seen this before spake of the of the
resurrection of Christ. He, meaning
David has seen this before, spake of the
resurrection of who?
>> Christ.
>> Jesus Christ. Go ahead.
>> That his soul was not left in hell.
>> That his soul was not left in hell or
the grave. Go ahead.
>> Neither his flesh did SEEK CORRUPTION.
>> AND NEITHER DID his flesh SEE
CORRUPTION. SO WHAT WAS NAILED TO THE
CROSS? HIS BODY. WHAT WAS THE OFFERING
FOR OUR SIN? HIS SOUL. BECAUSE THE SOUL
IS THE BODY. WHAT CAME OUT THE GRAVE?
HIS FLESH. WHAT ALSO CAME OUT THE GRAVE?
HIS SOUL. BECAUSE HIS FLESH AND BODY IS
THE SAME AS A SOUL. SAME THING. AND HE'S
the captain of our salvation. That means
whatever happened to him, we have the
same form and factor. He became one of
us.
So apparently we still have to have the
same thing. Flesh that is considered the
same thing as the soul. This is simple.
That's the end of 31.
>> That's the end of 31.
>> Perfect. Let's go to Acts 13.
Acts 13.
That's why when I go to a funeral and I
hear them teach wrong, IT MAKES MY SKIN
CRAWL cuz I'm LIKE, YOU HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT. AND YOU WERE
UP there preaching people.
My skin crawls
when I see how bad. That's why I said
the blind shall lead the blind and they
both shall fall in the what? In the pit.
Acts
13 and 32. 13 and 32.
13-32. Let because I need to verify and
prove this by reading, not by my
opinion. 13-32. When you get there, go
ahead and read. And we declare unto you
glad tidings, how that the the promise
which was made unto the fathers, God
hath fulfilled the same unto us their
children, and that he hath raised up
Jesus again.
>> Right? He raised up Jesus again. Go
ahead.
>> As it is also written in the second
Psalm,
>> thou art my son, this day have I
begotten thee.
>> So thou art my son, this day have I
begotten thee. Meaning the day that he
was resurrected, he was now considered
the son of God. He was the son of man
when he was in the flesh, but then he
called himself the son of God after the
resurrection even though him and the
father are equal. And we can read this.
Go ahead. And as concerning that he
raised him up from the dead.
>> As he raised him up from the dead. Go
ahead
>> now. No more to return to corruption.
>> No more to return to corruption. Go
ahead.
>> He said on this wise,
>> right?
>> I will give you the secure mercies of
David.
>> I will give you the sure mercies of
David. Who is the sure mercies of David?
Jesus. Jesus came through David's
lineage by way of Mary. Go ahead.
>> Wherefore he saith also in another psalm
>> in another psalm. Go ahead.
>> Thou shalt not suffer thy holy one to
see corruption.
>> And we already read that other psalm,
didn't we? Thou shalt not suffer thy
holy one to see corruption. Verse 36.
>> For David after he had served his own
generation,
>> he served his own generation just LIKE
BUOIE. BUOY HAS served his generation
and now what are we TRYING TO DO? WE ARE
TRYING TO SERVE our generation. Go
ahead.
>> By the will of God fell fell on sleep.
>> Fell asleep. In other words, died. Go
ahead.
>> Fell on sleep and was laid unto his
fathers and saw corruption
>> and he was laid up with his fathers. In
other words, he was dead. HE WAS BURIED.
AND KING DAVID HAS DECOMPOSED.
So that psalm in Psalm 16 cannot be
talking about David. It has to be
talking about Christ who saw no
corruption. Do y'all see this?
>> Yes.
>> Go ahead.
>> But he who God raised again saw no
corruption.
>> But he who God raised again, which is
talking Jesus, saw no corruption.
Saw no corruption.
Psalms chapter 3. Psalms chapter 3. the
more and more you can kind of see Jesus
and his body, his resurrection, his
death, and even what he did after he
resurrected. A lot of people don't know
what he did after he resurrected. We do.
A lot of people don't know why. Well,
Jared, why did it get dark for three
hours? I'm not telling you. That's a
secret. But we know why.
Well, Jared, why? Why this? Why that?
Hold up. I thought YOU WAS A CHRISTIAN.
WHY ARE YOU COMING TO THE ISRAELITE THAT
BELIEVES IN CHRIST? OH, BECAUSE WE ARE
THE first century Christians. The fourth
century is where the remix came in. The
fourth century is where Constantine
changed everything because he was trying
to assault the Jews. That's why
Constantine tried to pattern himself
after the Flavian dynasty. Who were the
Flavians? They were the ones that was
trying to kill the Jews by any means
necessary. They were the ones that
surrounded Jerusalem and tore it down.
But Constantine wanted to tear it down
from the inside by eroding the doctrine.
And we are in these days where the
doctrine has been eroded.
But the word of God stands tall.
Psalms 3 and verse one. Psalms 3 and
verse one. Well, brother Jared, didn't
Constantine become a Christian? I could
ask you a few different questions about
Constantine and you'll be like, "Oh, I
didn't know that. Oh, I didn't know
that. Oh, I didn't know that. Right. You
think Satan started lying in this
generation? He been lying since the
Garden of Eden. You think ain't no lies
back there that you got to investigate?
Psalms chapter 3.
See, y'all got the law. We got If that's
the case, then how come I know so much
about Christ? How come I know things
about Christ that you don't know? And
I'm only showing a smidg of what we
know.
Psalms 3 and verse one. 3 and 1. When
you get there, go ahead and read.
>> Lord, how are they increased that
trouble me? Many are they that rise up
against me.
>> That's right.
>> Many there be which say of my soul.
>> Uhhuh.
>> There is no help for him in God. Sah.
>> They see they say God ain't going to
help him. That's what they said about
Christ. God ain't going to help him
because they thought he was smitten by
God. Go ahead. But thou, oh Lord, are a
shield for for me by glory and the
lifter and the lifter up of mine head.
>> Uhhuh.
>> I cried unto the Lord with my voice.
>> I cried to the Lord. Go ahead.
>> And he heard And he heard me out of his
holy hill.
>> And he heard me from heaven. Go ahead.
>> Say,
>> uh-huh.
>> I laid me down to and slept.
>> I laid me down and slept. This means
Jesus Christ had died.
Laid me down and slept. Well, see,
brother Jay, when Jesus died, that was
the end of the law. That was the end of
the Old Testament. That was the end of
the prophecies. Then I would have to
stop this verse and not read any
further. But because after he died, some
happened, WHICH MEANS I CAN'T STOP THE
word of God. Finish that verse out.
>> I awaken. I awoke. In other words, he
woke from sleep or he resurrected from
the dead. Go ahead.
>> For the Lord sustained me.
>> For the Lord sustained me. That's why he
didn't see corruption.
Because the resurrection scriptures
prove that the Old Testament is still
intact.
It's Gentiles that have mistaught that.
That's the end of verse five.
>> That's the end of five.
>> Perfect. Let's go now to Psalm 30. Psalm
30.
Psalm chapter 30.
And we're gonna pick it up at verse one.
Too much information. That's why He and
it's like all you have to do is like
take him serious when he said he blessed
the Sabbath day and made it holy. That's
why you will always learn more
information today than any other day of
the week. All I guarantee you
Friday night,
>> well, which is the deadliest day of the
week because that's when most people are
breaking the Sabbath. That's why they
said, "How come Friday is the deadliest
day of the week?" No, you're talking
Friday nights because that's breaking
the Sabbath. That's why the Lord is
jumping on them and correcting them. The
soul that sinnth it shall die. And the
soul is a car accident away from death.
Psalm 30 and verse one. When you get
there, go ahead and read.
>> I will extol thee, oh Lord.
>> For thou hast lifted up, lifted me up.
>> Lifted me up. Go ahead.
>> And hast not made my foes to rejoice
over me.
>> That's right. Go ahead.
>> Oh Lord my God.
>> Right.
>> I cried unto thee.
>> I cried unto thee. Go ahead.
>> And thou hast healed me.
>> And you have healed me. Go ahead. Oh
Lord, thou has brought up my soul from
the grave.
>> You have brought up my what?
>> Soul.
>> You brought up my soul from the grave.
Because they'll see what they'll do is
they'll say, "Well, see that hell meant
something different and he really went
over there." But when you keep reading
more Bible, you realize what came from
the grave. The actual burial site was a
soul. That's why THEY SAY THE TOMB WAS
EMPTY. HAPPY EASTER. NO, don't Easter
that.
Uh-uh. Nowhere in the Bible does it give
you instructions on Easter. It tells you
about the Pass. So, so I'm not going to
take his resurrection and and connect it
with Gentile paganism.
Nope.
>> In fact, that's really Zonian paganism
for those that do the research. That's
that's even further than the Gentiles.
Go ahead. Verse three from the top.
>> Oh Lord, thou has brought up my soul
from the grave.
>> Uhhuh. Thou hast kept me alive that I
should not go down to the pit.
>> That's right. So now we know what came
from the pit. What came from the grave?
It was a soul. Let's go now to Psalms
I'm sorry to Romans 8. We got two more
spots. Romans 8. We got two more spots.
I need another water. I don't know. I
maybe I didn't drink enough water at
home today. I don't know what it is. I'm
just thirsty.
Maybe I should leave the kids fruit
punch alone.
>> I remember my faults this day.
[laughter]
Romans chapter 8 in the New Testament.
Still got it. Romans 8. Because
say, "Well, brother Jared, you read a
lot of Old Testament. We we read old and
new. Didn't we read some new? Y
>> let's read some more new to show that
Paul knew these concepts.
Romans 8 and verse 14. Romans 8 and 14.
When you get there, go ahead and read.
>> For as many as are led by the spirit of
God.
>> Okay. Now, what is the spirit? This
spirit means the word of God. Those that
are being led by the word of God, go
ahead.
>> They are the sons of God.
>> Right. And and sometimes I I think of
the spirit of God almost like lyrics of
a song. You know how some people like
really know those lyrics all the way
down? They know the chorus. They know
the entry. They know the outro. They
know these lyrics real well. The word of
God are just like lyrics. That's why
it's not called Songs of Solomon.
Songs
of um of Moses, but it's like lyrics.
That's why we know how to recite them.
Go ahead.
>> For ye have not received the spirit of
bondage again to fear, right? Right. But
ye have received the spirit of God.
>> Did we finish 14? Led by the spirit of
God or what? I'm sorry.
>> Yeah. They are the sons of God.
>> Okay. I just want to make sure. They are
the sons of God. So when you're being
led by the words of God, you are the son
of God. This here is talking about the
son of God in righteousness. You are not
the son of God in power. Only Jesus has
that according to Romans chapter one. In
other words, we're we're RSVPing
to be on that list. But right now, we
we're just in the book of life. because
we're operating by the spirit. Go ahead.
>> For ye have not received the spirit of
bondage again to fear.
>> Uhhuh. In other words, that that's a
different spirit. That's a spirit of
disobedience. Go ahead.
>> But ye have received the spirit of
adoption.
>> Spirit of adoption because we are aiming
to be adopted by God at the appointed
time. Either first resurrection or
second resurrection. The two witnesses
are adopted right before the first
resurrection with the shout of the angel
in Revelation 11. That's when they get
adopted and go from man to God,
from man to spirit. Go ahead.
>> Whereby we cry aba father.
>> Right? Because right now we are crying
saying that the Lord is our father. But
some people that disobey the word of
God, Jesus says Satan is they father. Go
ahead.
>> The spirit itself beareth witness with
our spirit.
>> Uhhuh. The word of God is in line with
what we saying. Go ahead.
>> That we are the children of God. that we
are the children of God. Go ahead.
>> And if children, then heirs. Heirs of
God.
>> And if we're children, we're heirs. Heir
means we will inherit. We don't have it
yet. But someone will say, "Well, I'm
born again already. I'm already saved."
And I'm like, "Oh, is that so? What are
you saved from when great tribulation
hasn't hit yet? The lake of fire ain't
here yet. The Lord hasn't come back and
caused h blood to rise to the horse's
bridal for 200 miles. What have you been
saved from yet? That's why we did that
lesson about what saved really means,
>> right?
>> Didn't we cover that?
>> Yes, sir.
>> I'm just showing what how this is
showing. Nah, you don't have what you
think you have. Go ahead.
>> And joint hes with Christ.
>> Joint hes with Christ. So, whatever
Christ is going to inherit, we will be a
joint heir to inherit what Christ
inherits. And Christ is going to inherit
a kingdom, which is really the earth.
But if everyone say they go to heaven,
then how you going joint air with
Christ? He hasn't even sat on the throne
of David yet,
>> right?
>> And there's going to be thrones of David
in Jerusalem according to Psalms 121. So
what are you talking about? Go ahead.
>> If so be that we suffered with him that
we may be also glorified together.
>> That's right. Cuz right now we going
through the suffering. Right. Right.
>> We are not the one that's elevated on
high. We going through the suffering
like he wasn't at that point in time.
Right. So it says that uh if we so
suffer with him then the same glory
which was revealed in him shall be
revealed in us. What glory is this? The
same way during the transfiguration his
body started shining like light and he
had Moses and Elijah and their body
shine like light. That's the GLORY YOU
EXPECT TO get when you become a son of
God or GET THAT NEW BODY. This regular
body don't shine unless you put too much
baby oil on it. Then that's only way
shiny. Now that boy forehead is shining.
But that new body, no matter what
nationality you are, you are not no
longer son of man. You have transferred
to being son of God. Different body the
same way Jesus got it. You remember the
disciples after he resurrected, they
were all in the same room with the door
locked and he started popping up in the
room. Right.
>> Right. It it wasn't a knock at the door.
He ain't just because that's what that's
what a spiritual body can do. Angels can
can do that, too. Go ahead. For I reckon
that the sufferings of the of this
present time are not worthy to be
compared with the glory which shall be
revealed
>> which shall be revealed in us.
>> In us.
>> Uh-huh.
>> For the earnest expectation of the
creature waited for the manifestation of
the sons of God.
>> And they don't know that that this
creature because we all are created to
to be a creature. You have to be
created. We all are expecting
and we are waiting for the manifestation
of the sons of God. So if you already
HAVE IT, WHAT ARE YOU EXPECTING? IF YOU
ARE ALREADY SAVED, then what are you
expecting to come in the future? Just
like when you had layaway, you will pay
a portion here and a portion this month
and a portion when you get that check,
right? Expecting to get it in the
future. But if you have it already, you
just use credit.
This is on layaway. Big difference. Go
ahead.
>> For the creature was made subject to
vanity, right? Not willingly, but by
reasons of him who have subjected the
same in hope.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Because the creature itself also shall
be delivered from the bondage of
corruption.
>> Shall be. In other words, it ain't here
yet. That's why we can read that David
saw corruption. It shall be delivered
from the bondage of corruption. In other
words, from death. Go ahead. into the
glorious liberty of the children of God.
>> INTO THE GLORIOUS THE BRIGHT SHINING
LIBERTY OF the sons of God. Go ahead.
>> For we know that the whole creation
groanth and travaleth in pain together
until now.
>> Uh-huh. Cuz the whole creation is still
groaning because it hasn't happened yet.
The only one that came from the grave is
Jesus Christ that got that new body. The
rest of the creation has been groaning,
suffering through death. Go ahead.
>> And not only they, but ourselves also.
Not only they but US HERE IN THIS ROOM.
THIS INCLUDES us as what Paul is letting
you know. Go ahead.
>> Which have the first fruits of the
spirit.
>> Which have the first fruits of the what?
>> Spirit.
>> The first fruits of the spirit. That's
why we understand that on Pentecost that
represents the first fruit being offered
unto God. CUZ THIS IS INCLUDING YOU. YOU
ARE IN THE BIBLE WHETHER YOU KNOW IT or
not. Well, you can play the good part or
the bad part, but you are in the
scriptures.
Go ahead.
>> Even we ourselves grown within
ourselves, right?
>> Waiting for the adoption.
>> Waiting for the adoption. Groaning. Why?
Cuz you woke up out of bed. Your knees
was cracking too. Not just mine. Your
back was sore too. Not just mine. We are
groaning cuz we are in THE ORIGINAL
CREATION WAITING FOR THE manifestation
of the sons of God. Go ahead.
>> Waiting for the adoption to it. The the
>> we hold. We waiting for the adoption.
Right.
>> Right. So in other words, he said if we
maintain ourselves, he will adopt us.
And when we are adopted, we going go
from being sons of man to being sons of
God. We are waiting for adoption day. Go
ahead.
>> The redemption of our body.
>> The redemption OF OUR WHAT?
>> BODY.
>> BODY. YOU EXPECT TO GET A NEW BODY. THE
SAME way you already have one, you will
just get a new one, but it's going to
look just like how you look now. That's
why Peter was able to say, "Hold up,
MOSES AND ELIJAH, EVEN THOUGH THEY HAD A
DIFFERENT SHINING BODY,
which also lets you know that they hid
our images of the original people
because Peter knew exactly what Elijah
looked like and knew exactly what Moses
looked like." How come we can see
ancient Egyptian imagery, but we can't
see no ancient Israelite imagery? No.
Because Edom went to go hide the images
so they could say we're the Jews now.
The look like the Gentiles.
That's why they said, "Should we pay
taxes to Caesar?" He said, "Give me a
coin. Let me see it. Whose superscript
is on it? Caesar." He said, "Rent unto
Caesar." That was the Caesars. That look
like the Gentiles. But ren to God unto
God because we don't look alike.
But they could catch it.
They couldn't catch it.
What verse we at?
>> That was the end of 23.
>> End of 23. Go now to Psalms 49. And we
got one more spot. Psalm 49.
That's why in the last days, we going to
know who's who. Not by what they look
like, but by what they know.
by what they know.
And you notice it's not a whole lot of
people that want to have Bible study
with us
>> because it's going to cause some
correction.
>> We're not trying to beat nobody down.
We're just show what's right and what's
wrong.
There must be a reason someone is
confused about scripture, text,
prophecy, the gospels even
on your way here. Well, I can't on some
of y'all way here. Y'all probably took
495 like I took. Right.
>> Right.
>> And y'all saw that big old thing that
you as a kid you thought that was Disney
World, right? That wasn't Disney World.
That was a Mormon temple.
But the lies were exalted on high.
Who's this false angel called Moroni
that's over 495? Moroni is not here. The
Lord didn't speak to Joseph Smith and
give him golden plates. According to
their book, the Book of Mormon, I have a
whole nation named after me called the
Gerodites. Did y'all know that? That's
why when I was talking to my supervisor
at work one time, he gave me about a
half hour to expound the scriptures and
he was left speechless. He stopped being
a Mormon. Why? Because I'm recovering
those that have been caught by
deception.
if they will allow themselves to.
Psalms 49 and verse one.
I think someone said, well, I think what
was it? Brother Charles said, I brother
J, I ran into some Mormons. They were
like kids and they had to term elder on.
I said, how do you have some elder kids?
[laughter]
They mother dropped them off out the
minivan before they could be an elder to
come preach you. Then they had to go
back in the minivan. That don't make no
sense, does it?
Then they say, "Have you heard the
Gospel of Joseph Smith through the Book
of Mormon?" Interesting. Where was Jesus
born? The Book of Mormon says Jerusalem.
Well, my Bible says Bethlehem.
You see how easy it is to get around the
fall? It's very e It's very easy. I'm
not just saying that. I'm really telling
you, keep coming on the Sabbath day. And
religion is the easiest topic. I have
more problems at work than I have
dealing with the Bible.
But it's the opposite. So, I'm a great
poet, but I can't understand religion
because you got to keep the Sabbath day
to get it and and obey, of course.
Psalms 49. Psalms 49 and verse one.
Psalm 49 and verse one.
How are you a 14-year-old elder?
Your beard don't even connect yet.
Let me stop.
Psalm 491. When you get there, go ahead
and read. Hear this. All ye people.
>> All ye people. Go ahead.
>> Give ear. All ye inhabitants of the
world.
>> Go ahead. Jump down to verse six.
Everybody listen up. He's saying, go
ahead. Verse six.
>> They that trust in their wealth,
>> right?
>> And boast themselves in the multitude of
their riches,
>> right?
>> None of them can by any means redeem his
brother.
>> You can't redeem your brother no matter
how much money you have. Go ahead.
>> Nor give to God a ransom for him.
>> That's right. Go ahead. For the
redemption of their soul is precious and
it ceases forever.
>> Uh-huh. Go ahead.
>> That he should still live forever and
not see corruption.
>> Right? Because a soul can corrupt. But
you can't pay God to stop your soul from
dying. That's why the Catholic Church
when they dealt with those indulgences,
they say, "Pay this money and it will do
something such for uh get salvation for
whatever loved one." He's like, "Don't
even believe that stuff. Go ahead." For
he saith that wise men die, likewise the
fool and the and the brutish person
perish and leave their wealth to others.
>> Exactly. So just like everybody fall
subject to death, but it's about what
what happens when you wake up because
everyone they leave the inheritance to
different people, right? So we see that
happening in this present day. Jump down
to verse 14. Go ahead.
>> Like sheep, they are all laid in their
grave,
>> right? Everyone's laid in the grave. Go
ahead.
Death shall feed on them.
>> And death feeds on all of us. Go ahead.
>> And the upright shall have dominion over
them in the morning. And and their
beauty shall consume in the grave from
their dwelling.
>> It says the upright shall have dominion
over them in the morning. That's why it
says weeping may endure for a night, but
joy comes in the morning. This morning
is talking about during the first
resurrection.
they are given power this morning
because just like it's using morning the
same way we use sleep to go to sleep
right to reference death and then
morning is usually when you get up he's
talking about that's why he says I'm the
bright morning star
>> Satan's the son of the morning so when
Jesus returns that is the time of the
morning that's when they going to have
dominion because those that overcome
shall inherit all things go ahead
>> but God will redeem my soul from the
power of the grave God will redeem my
soul from the what?
>> Power of the grave.
>> Go ahead.
>> For he shall receive me. Say lie.
>> For he shall receive me. Your soul is
being redeemed from the grave. Which
means you cannot stay in the grave.
Everyone that has ever died must wake up
and report on judgment day.
That is the great reporting. It's just
that if you wake up in the first
resurrection, you good to go. You
helping him administer judgment day. You
are not being judged.
Man, if I had no idea about that. 1
Corinthians 15, last spot. 1 Corinthians
15.
I had no idea that by keeping the
Sabbath day, I am preparing myself for
the first resurrection
because the 10,00ear reign is the real
Sabbath. So when you keep preparing and
preparing and preparing, when the time
comes, this ain't new to you. You like,
"Oh, we've been doing this." And you
know how to get everything in order,
right?
Just like people before us that have
already died know how to get things in
order.
Just like when David come, HE REALLY
GOING TO GET things in order, right?
First Corinthians 15. Paul, let's make
it plain again. Let's make it plain,
Paul. 1 Corinthians 15 and 35.
15 and 35.
When you get there, let's start reading.
>> But some men will say,
>> somebody may say, go ahead.
>> How are the dead raised up?
>> Right?
>> And with what body do they come?
>> How are the dead raised up? And with
with what body do they come? They don't
even ask that question nowadays because
they say they're already in heaven. But
someone's going to say, "How are the
dead raised up?" Go ahead.
Thou fool that which thou seest is not
quickened except it die.
>> Right? That which you sow in other words
the body that goes in the ground just
like a seed. Go ahead.
>> And that which say is not quickened or
in other words made alive except it dies
first. Now go ahead give me 37.
>> And that which thou seest thou seest not
that body that shall be. In other words,
what you put in the grave or what is
sold and goes in the ground is not the
same thing that comes out the ground.
That's where they get thriller and all
that stuff where oh they popped up
decomposed too. No, he said the thing
that shall be is not the same that you
put in the ground. Go ahead.
>> But bear grain
>> but it bears grain. All of us are
considered grain until we go on the
ground. Then we have to then the Lord
takes over from there because we keep
forgetting what the L what is the Lord
harvesting? Why does he called us the
wheat and the tears and all these
different uh uh plant references?
Because us going in the ground, he's
looking to harvest something different
and it's not regular grain. Go ahead.
>> It may chance of wheat
>> wheat
>> or of some other grain.
>> Uh-huh. Go ahead.
>> But God giveth it a body as it had
pleased him. God has given everyone a
body as it has pleased him. Those that
are obedient get a glorious body. The
disobedient get a body that all I know
is it doesn't give you much detail about
it. It just lets you know you don't want
to have it. Go ahead.
>> And to every seed his own body.
>> Every seed gets his own body. Jump down
to 42. 42.
>> So also it's the resurrection of the
dead. Now Paul is saying this is the
same thing as the resurrection of the
dead. Go ahead.
>> It is sown in corruption.
>> It is. So the what you put in the body
corros or corrupts. It is sown in
corruption. Go ahead.
>> It is raised in incorruption.
>> But what comes out the grave is raised
in incorruption. Why do I know that?
Because Jesus gave us the example. He's
the foreigner. He's the author and the
finisher. So now that we see what Jesus
h what happened with him, we know what's
going to happen with us. We must be
raised from the dead and there cannot be
a body STILL IN THE GRAVE SITE, CAN IT?
Because when Jesus was in the grave, was
there still a body in there? Yes or no?
So it has to be the same thing here.
Why? Because he's resurrecting us. Hit
that. Hit 42 again from the top.
>> 42. So also is the resurrection of the
dead. It is sown incorruption. It is
raised in incorruption.
>> Right. Now jump to verse 44. Go ahead.
>> It is sown a natural body.
>> It is sown. We all have that natural
body. Go ahead.
>> It is raised a spiritual body.
>> But what is raised is a spiritual body.
Your body and your soul is changed. Go
ahead.
>> There is a natural body
>> which we all have. Go ahead.
>> And there is a spiritual body.
>> And that's the one we want to take over.
That's why he said in my father's house
there are many mansions
because that mansion represents a more
powerful body than this house that you
have today.
>> Go ahead.
>> Go to 46 or 47.
>> Uh uh that was 44.
>> That was the end of uh 44. Yes.
>> Yeah. Give me 45.
>> And so it is written.
>> So it is written. Go ahead.
>> The first man Adam was made a living
soul.
>> The first man Adam Hold on. It didn't
say a soul was put inside Adam. Uh,
don't say that.
>> It said he was made a living soul. Go
ahead.
>> The last Adam was made a quickening
spirit.
>> And the last Adam was made a quickening
spirit. The last Adam is Jesus Christ.
>> The first Adam. Adam was the beginning
OF HIS WHOLE CREATION. Who was the last
Adam? Jesus. Why? Because he's the
beginning of the creation of God.
That's what that is. Adam named
everything on the creation, didn't he?
That's an elephant. That's an alligator.
That's a turtle. Why do you think Jesus
Christ is going to give us all new
names, put on the white stone, and given
unto us?
>> Cuz the last Adam names all everything
from the new creation.
>> Go ahead.
>> The first
>> Go ahead. What verse we at?
>> Uh, just hit 45 over. Just hit 45 over.
>> 45.
>> Uh-huh. And so it is written, the first
man, Adam, was made a living soul.
>> Right?
>> The last Adam was made a quickening
spirit.
>> A quickening spirit. And give me 47.
>> The first man is of the earth, earthy,
>> right?
>> The second man is the Lord from heaven.
>> The second one is the Lord from heaven.
So the last man, Adam, is talking about
Jesus. I said this the last spot. I got
the one verse in there. Just one. Just
one. Just one. Revelation
3 and14.
Revelation 3 and4. The spirit just hit
me so I had to read it because I was
like, "Okay, that connects and dots." He
right. Revelation 3 and 14. Give me that
one verse.
>> 3 and 14. Right.
>> And unto the angel of the church of
Leodysans,
>> and the angel that's speaking to the
church of Leodysians, this is the worst
church out of all seven of Leodysans. Go
ahead.
>> Right.
>> Right. These things said the these
things say the Lord said the amen.
>> The amen.
>> The faithful and true witness.
>> The faithful and true witness. That's
what Jesus is. Go ahead.
>> The beginning of the creation of God.
That doesn't mean that Jesus created
because he existed. That's why he's
called the ancient of days. He existed
way before. But what it is is when he
died and resurrected, he went from being
man to becoming God. AND HE'S THE
BEGINNING or the last man, ADAM, OF THE
CREATION OF GOD. SO WHAT the rest of us
were meant to be. We He's not done
making us. We're still in the kitchen.
The finished product was when not when
your man is still subject to death like
Adam and Eve were. The last product IS
WHEN YOU CANNOT DIE. AND THAT'S WHEN he
will rest again for another thousand
years. And that is the soul is not
inside the body, but the soul is the
body. I thank you for your time.
I only added one. Go ahead. [music]
[music]
>> [music]
>> Not tomorrow. Not tomorrow.